纸浆:名词 1.柔软、潮湿、没有形状的物质
2.内容庸俗、印刷粗糙、纸张简陋的杂志
——《美国文物词典》新大学版
算了 太冒险了 我不干这鸟事了
Forget it  It's too risky  I'm through doing that shit
你每次都这样说
You always say that, the same thing every time
我不干了…再也不干了…太危险了…
I'm through, never again, too dangerous
我知道我老这么说 可我也一直都是对的
I know that's what I always say  I'm always right, too
但是你过两天就会忘了
But you forget about it in a day or two
“忘记”的日子结束了 “记住”的日子刚刚开始！
Well, the days of me forgetting are over and the days of me remembering have just begun
知道么 你每次这样说的时候听起来像什么?
You know when you go on like this what you sound like?
像他妈个明智的人
Sound like a sensible fucking man,that's what I sound like.
你像只鸭子 嘎嘎嘎……
You sound like a duck  Quack, quack, quack
相信我 你不会再听到了 以后我再也不冒险了
Take heart, cause you're never gonna have to hear it again since I'm never gonna do it again
所以你再也不会听到我叫唤为什么不想冒险了
you're never gonna have to hear me quack about how I'm never gonna do it again
得过了今晚
After tonight
那我还有一整晚可叫呢
Correct  I got all tonight to quack
再来点咖啡吗?
Can I get anyone more coffee?
谢谢你！
Oh, yes  Thank you
不客气
You're welcome
我说 现在这样冒险无异于抢银行
I mean, the way it is now you're taking the same risk as when you rob a bank
甚至风险更大 抢银行还容易些
You take more of a risk  Banks are easier
遇到抢劫 联邦银行根本就不作为
Federal banks ain't supposed to stop you in any way during a robbery
他们有保险的 何必来找死？
They're insured  Why should they give a fuck?
你甚至连枪都不用带
You don't even need a gun in a federal bank
听说有个家伙走进银行把大哥大交给出纳员
I heard about this one bloke He walks into a bank with a portable phone  He gives the phone to the teller
电话那头的人说…
bloke on the other end of the phone says
我们抓住了这个家伙女儿
We got this guy's little girl
如果不把所有钱给他 我们就把她杀掉！
If you don't give him all your money we're gonna kill her
管用吗?
Did it work?
当然管用啦！一个傻瓜拎着支大哥大走进银行…
Fucking way, it works  That's what I'm talking about! Knucklehead walks into a bank with a telephone
没用手枪 也没用猎枪 一部傻逼电话就把银行洗劫了
not a pistol, not a shotgun a fucking phone  Cleans the place out
一根指头都他妈不必动！
They don't even lift a fucking finger
那小女孩呢?
Did they hurt the little girl?
谁知道? 也许根本就没有什么小女孩
I don't know  Probably never was a girl in the first place
这故事的重点不是那个小女孩 重点是…
The point of the story isn't the girl  The point of the story is
他们抢银行居然用的是一部大哥大！
they robbed a bank with a telephone
你想抢银行?
You want to rob banks?
我没想抢银行 我只是说抢银行比我们之前的活容易多了
I'm not saying I want to rob banks  If we did, it would be easier than what we been doing
不再抢酒行了?
No more liquor stores?
刚刚我说的是废话吗？当然不再抢酒行了！
What we been talking about? Yeah, no more liquor stores
酒行可不像以前好搞了 大部分开酒行的都是外国佬
Besides, it ain't the giggle it used to be  There's too many foreigners own liquor stores
越南人、韩国人 他们连英文都他妈不会说！
Vietnamese, Koreans, they don't even speak fucking English
你叫他们“倒空收银机”？他们听得懂个屁啊!
You tell 'em, Empty out the register  they don't know what the fuck you're talking about
和他们根本没法沟通 到时候就只有干掉他们！
They make it too personal  We keep on, one of these gook fucker's gonna make us kill him
我不想杀人
I'm not gonna kill anybody
我也不想
I don't want to kill anybody, either
但是他们会把我们逼到那种你死我亡的境地
But they'll probably put us in a situation where it's us or them
如果不是亚洲猪 就是他妈的老不死的犹太佬！
And if it's not the gooks, it's these old fucking Jews who've owned the store for fifteen fucking generations
他们经营这些店都他妈十五代了！
who've owned the store for fifteen fucking generations
想象下 一个臭老头坐在柜台里
You got Grandpa Irving sitting behind the counter
手里他妈的拿把马格南
（一种大威力手枪）…
with a fucking Magnum in his hand
你什么都不带拿支大哥大走进去试试……
Try walking into one of those places with nothing but a phone
看看会是什么结果？我们可不能这么干！
See how far that gets you  Fuck it  We're out of it
那还能干什么？乖乖地找工作么？
Yeah, well, what then? Day jobs?
死也不要        那怎么办?
Not in this life  What, then?
小弟！咖啡！
Garcon! Coffee!
这里
This place
我是小妹！
Garcon means  boy
这里?一间咖啡店?
This place? A coffee shop?
有问题吗?
What's wrong with that?
没人抢过餐厅   有何不可？
Nobody ever robs restaurants  Why not?
酒吧、酒行和加油站
Bars, liquor stores, gas stations
抢其中任何一个都会脑袋搬家
you get your head blown off sticking up one of them
可是你想想 抢餐馆呢？
Restaurants, on the other hand,
肯定打他们个措手不及!
you catch with their pants down
因为他们绝对想不到会有人来抢劫
They're not expecting to get robbed  Not as expecting, anyway
我敢打赌这种地方也没人会逞英雄…
I bet you could cut down on the hero factor in a place like this
没错！
Correct！
这种地方和银行一样是有保险的
Same as banks, these places are insured
经理 他何必自找麻烦
Manager    he don't give a fuck
他只想在你影响到他晚上的生意之前赶快把你弄走
He's just trying to get you out the door before you start plugging the diners
服务员？少他妈扯了！
Waitresses? Fucking forget it
她们才不会为了老板吃子弹
No way they're taking a bullet for the register
还有小工 累死累活地工作50小时才挣1美元
Busboys, some wetback getting paid $1 50 an hour
会他妈介意你拿他老板的钱？
really give a fuck you're stealing from the owner?
那些嘴里含着食物的客人根本就反应不过来
Customers sitting with food in their mouths,They don't know what's going on,
前一分钟还在吃丹佛煎蛋 后一分钟就被人用枪指着脸
One minute they're having a Denver omelette next minute, someone's sticking a gun in their face
所以…我有个主意…
See, I got the idea
上次抢酒行的情况还记得吗？
last liquor store we stuck up  Remember?
顾客一直上门
All the customers kept coming in?
记得
Yeah
你想到要抢他们的钱包
You got the idea taking their wallets
那主意很棒！      谢谢！
Now, that was a good idea  Thank you
钱包里的钱比收银机的还多！      没错！
Made more from the wallets than we did from the register  Yes, we did
餐厅里有很多很多顾客……
A lot of people come into restaurants
很多很多钱包……
A lot of wallets
聪明吧?
Pretty smart, huh?
太聪明了！
Pretty smart
我准备好了 行动吧 就现在 来吧！
I'm ready  Let's do it  Right now, right here  Come on
好吧! 老规矩 你控制顾客 我搞定雇员
All right  Same as last time, remember? You're crowd control  I handle employees
我爱你南瓜仔！
I love you, Pumpkin
我爱你小兔兔！
I love you, Honey Bunny
都别动 抢劫了！
Everybody, be cool! This is a robbery!
谁他妈敢乱动一下 我就把你们这些杂种统统杀光！
Any of you fucking pricks move and I'll execute every motherfucking last one of you!
昆汀·塔伦蒂诺作品
片名：低俗小说
约翰·特拉沃尔塔
萨缪尔·杰克逊
乌玛·瑟曼
哈维·凯特尔
蒂姆·罗斯
阿曼达·普拉莫
玛利亚·德·梅黛洛
文·瑞姆斯
艾瑞克·斯托罗兹
罗珊娜·阿奎特
克里斯托弗·沃肯
布鲁斯·威利斯
领衔主演
那么 再跟我讲讲那些地下酒吧
OK, so tell me again about the hash bars
想听点什么?
OK  What you want to know?
在那儿吸大麻是合法的对吗?
Hash is legal there, right?
没错 不过不是100%合法 你不能走进一家餐馆
Yeah, it's legal, but it ain't 100% legal  You just can't walk into a restaurant
然后卷支大麻烟就开始吸
roll a joint, and start puffing away
我的意思是 他们希望你在家里或者指定场所吸
I mean, they want you to smoke in your home or certain designated places
就是那些地下酒吧吗?
And those are hash bars?
这么说吧 买大麻烟是合法的 持有大麻是合法的
Yeah, it breaks down like this  It's legal to buy it, it's legal to own it
如果你是地下酒吧的老板 出售大麻也是合法的
and if you're the proprietor of a hash bar it's legal to sell it
携带大麻也行 但这并不重要 因为 听好了…
It's legal to carry it, but    but that doesn't matter cause, get a load of this, all right?
要是被阿姆斯特丹的条子拦下来 他们搜你身是违法的
If you get stopped by a cop in Amsterdam it's illegal for them to search you
在阿姆斯特丹警察没有搜身的权力
I mean, that's a right the cops in Amsterdam don't have
靠 伙计 我要去 这就是我想要的 我他妈也要去！
Oh, man, I'm going  That's all there is to it  I'm fucking going
我就知道你会喜欢这个！
I know, baby  You'd dig it the most
你知道欧洲什么最有意思吗?
But you know what the funniest thing about Europe is?
什么?      就是那一点点的小差异
What? It's the little differences
就是和我们这里一模一样的东西
I mean, they got the same shit over there that they got here
到了他们那里就会有一点点小差异
but it's just a little different
举个例?
Example?
你可以在阿姆斯特丹的电影院买到啤酒
You can go to a movie theater in Amsterdam and buy a beer,
我说的不是纸杯的那种 他们是用玻璃杯装的
And I don't mean just like in no paper cup I'm talking about a glass of beer
你在巴黎的麦当劳也能买到啤酒
And in Paris, you can buy a beer at McDonald's
还有 你知道巴黎的“四分之一磅吉士汉堡” 怎么叫吗?
（在中国叫吉士汉堡，麦当劳的招牌之一）
And you know what they call a Quarter-Pounder with Cheese in Paris?
不叫“四分之一磅吉士汉堡” ?
They don't call it a Quarter-Pounder with Cheese?
不 伙计 他们那里用公制的 不知道四分之一磅是他妈多重
No, man, they got the metric system there  They wouldn't know what the fuck a Quarter-Pounder is
那叫什么?
What do they call it?
皇家吉士堡
They call it a  Royale with Cheese
皇家吉士堡?          没错
Royale with Cheese  That's right
巨无霸叫什么呢?
What do they call a Big Mac?
巨无霸还是巨无霸不过前面加一个乐字
Big Mac's a Big Mac, but they call it Le Big Mac
乐巨无霸
Le Big Mac
皇堡又叫什么?
（汉堡王的招牌堡）
What do they call a Whopper?
不知道 我没去吃过汉堡王
I don't know  I didn't go into Burger King
你知道荷兰人在薯条加什么代替番茄酱吗？
You know what they put on French fries in Holland instead of ketchup?
加什么?          美奶滋（既蛋黄酱）
What? Mayonnaise
我操！           呵呵……
Goddamn！     Ha ha ha…
我看他们这么吃的 伙计
I've seen 'em do it, man.
他们他妈的把薯条浸在那鸡巴玩意儿里吃
They fucking drown 'em in that shit.
我们真该带带猎枪来处理这种事情
They fucking drown 'em in that shit  We should have shotguns for this kind of deal
上面有多少人？
How many up there?
三、四个吧
Three or four
包括我们的人?
That's counting our guy?
不确定
I'm not sure
所以有可能五个人
So that means it could be up to five guys up there?
很有可能
It's possible
真他妈该拿猎枪来的！
We should have fucking shotguns
她叫什么?
What's her name?
米娅        米娅?
Mia  Mia?
马瑟勒斯怎么认识她的
How did Marsellus and her meet?
谁知道呢 就这么认识的
I don't know  However people meet people
她当过演员
She used to be an actress
是吗?她演过什么?
Oh, really? She do anything I'd have seen?
我想她最重要的演出就是一个样片儿吧
I think her biggest deal was she starred in a pilot
“样片”是什么玩意?
Pilot? What's a pilot?
呃…看过电视剧吧?
Well, you know the shows on TV?
我从不看电视的
I don't watch TV
那你知道有一种发明叫电视机…
Yeah, but you are aware that there's an invention called television
电视机上面要演电视节目吧？
and on this invention they show shows, right?
知道
Yeah
他们选择电视剧的方式就是先拍一集 这第一集就叫"样片"
The way they pick TV shows, they make one show  That show's called a pilot
拍好就给选片的人看
Then they show that one show to the people who pick shows
根据样片决定哪个可以继续拍下去
and on the strength of that one show they decide if they want to make more shows
被选中的就成为电视节目
Some get chosen and become television programs
没被选上就什么也不是
Some don't, become nothing
她演的就什么也不是
She starred in one of the ones that became nothing
你记得那个安特万·罗卡莫拉吗？
You remember Antwan Rockamora?
黑人和萨摩亚人混血的绰号叫“恐怖东尼”的那个
Half-black, half-Samoan used to call him "Tony Rocky Horror".
呃…那个胖子吗?
Yeah, maybe  Fat, right?
我才不会叫这哥们儿胖子呢 他确实有点超重
I wouldn't go so far as to call the brother fat  I mean, he got a weight problem
可这黑鬼能做什么？他是个萨摩亚裔！
（萨摩亚裔通常都超肥的）
What's the nigger gonna do, he's Samoan
我知道你说的是谁了他怎么了？
Yeah, I think I know who you mean  What about him?
马瑟勒斯把他修理惨了
Well, Marsellus fucked him up good
据说是因为马瑟勒斯·华莱士的老婆
Word around the campfire is it was on account of Marsellus Wallace's wife
他做了什么？操她了？      不不不 没这么糟
So, what'd he do, fuck her? No, no, no, no, no  Nothing that bad
那是怎么一回事?
Well, then, what, then?
替她做了脚部按摩
Gave her a foot massage
脚部按摩？
A foot massage?
仅此而已?
That's it?
马瑟勒斯怎么整的他?
Then what did Marsellus do?
派了几个手下去他的住处把他弄到公寓楼的露台上
Sent a couple of cats over to his place They took him out on his patio,
然后拖上阳台 黑鬼从四楼摔了下来
threw his ass over the balcony  Nigger fell four stories
楼下有个玻璃顶棚的小花园 像一个温室
They had a little garden down at the bottom enclosed in glass, like a greenhouse
那黑鬼就摔里面去了
Nigger fell through that
从那以后 他就变得口吃了
Since then, he kind of developed a speech impediment
太丢脸了！
That's a damn shame
不过他这叫玩火自焚
But still, I have to say you play with matches, you get burned
怎么说?
What do you mean?
傻逼才敢替马瑟勒斯·华莱士的老婆做脚部按摩
You don't be giving Marsellus Wallace's new bride a foot massage
是马瑟勒斯太小题大作了吧?
You don't think he overreacted?
安特万大概没有料到马瑟勒斯的反应这么强烈
Well, Antwan probably didn't expect Marsellus to react the way he did,
但应该知道他肯定会有所反应
but he had to expect a reaction
只是脚部按摩 这能有什么？
It was a foot massage  A foot massage is nothing
我都会替我老妈做脚部按摩
I give my mother a foot massage
不 这是用手暧昧地抚摸马瑟勒斯的新婚妻子
No, it's laying hands in a familiar way on Marsellus' new wife,
有直接吃她的鲍鱼那么严重吗？没有
is it as bad as eating her pussy out? No,
不过他妈的性质也差不多了
but it's the same fucking ballpark
噢！噢！噢！就此打住…
Whoa, whoa, whoa, stop right there
口交和脚部按摩太他妈不同了
Eating a bitch out and giving a bitch a foot massage ain't even the same fucking thing
是不同… 不过也差不多了
It's not It's the same ballpark
不！性质他妈的完全不同！
Ain't no fucking ballpark, neither
也许你按摩的方式和我不同
Now, look, maybe your method of massage differs from mine
不过把手放在他脚上和把舌头插入她的神仙洞里
but you know touching his wife's feet and sticking your tongue in her holiest of holies
不是他妈的相同的性质 是他妈完全不同的两码事！
ain't the same fucking ballpark It ain't the same league It ain't even the same fucking sport
脚部按摩根本没什么！
Look, foot massages don't mean shit
你替人脚部按摩过吗?
Have you ever given a foot massage?
别在我面前说脚部按摩 我他妈是按摩大师！
Don't be telling me about foot massages  I'm the foot fucking master
经验丰富?
You given a lot of 'em?
当然 技术高超 不是盖的
Shit, yeah  Got my technique down and everything  I don't be tickling or nothing
那你会替男人做脚部按摩吗?
Would you give a guy a foot massage?
去你的！
Fuck you
你常做吗?          操！
You given 'em a lot? Fuck you
我很累 想来点脚底按摩
You know, I'm kind of tired  I could use a foot massage myself
你再闹 我就要翻脸了
Yo, yo, yo, man  You best back off  I'm getting a little pissed here
就是这里 没错
This is the door  There it is
几点了
What time you got?
七点二十二分
7:22 in the a m
还早 来 我们走走
No, it ain't quite time yet  Come on  Let's hang back
我不给男人做脚部按摩不代表马瑟勒斯是对的
Just 'cause I wouldn't give no man a foot massage don't make it right for Marsellus
把安特万从楼上仍进该死的玻璃花房摔成结巴太他妈过份了
to throw Antwan off a building into a glass motherfucking house fucking up the way the nigger talks
谁他妈要敢这样对我 他最好快来添我的屁股
That shit ain't right Motherfucker do that shit to me, he better paralyze my ass
因为我绝对要杀了那狗杂种报仇懂吗？
cause I'd kill the motherfucker you know what I'm saying?
我没说他是对的
I ain't saying it's right
但是你说脚部按摩根本没什么 这我不同意
But you're saying a foot massage don't mean nothing and I'm saying it does
我替很多女人做过脚部按摩 都“有什么”！
I've given a million ladies a million foot massages and they all meant something
大家都心照不宣 所以才他妈很爽！
Now, we act like they don't, but they do  That's what's so fucking cool about 'em
大家都能感觉到那种情欲 但不会说破
There's a sensuous thing going on where, you know you don't talk about it
男女各自心知肚明
but you know it, and she knows it
马瑟勒斯很清楚 安特万更他妈清楚
Fucking Marsellus knew it and Antwan should've fucking better known better
伙计 那可是他老婆！可不能拿这事儿开玩笑！
I mean, that's his fucking wife, man  This ain't a man with a sense of humor about this shit
懂我的意思了吗?
You know what I'm saying?
很有意思…走吧 该干活了
It's an interesting point  Come on  Let's get into character
她叫什么来着?
What's her name again?
米娅  米娅
Mia  Mia
干嘛对老大的女人感兴趣?
Why you so interested in big man's wife?
老大要去趟弗罗里达 叫我搞定她
Well, he's going out of town, Florida and he asked me if I'd take care of her while he's gone
搞定她?      别想歪 老兄
Take care of her? No, man  Just take her out
我只是负责陪她寻乐子 不让她无聊而已
You know, show her a good time  Make sure she don't get lonely
你要带米娅·华莱士出去约会?
You're gonna be taking Mia Wallace out on a date?
不是约会
It is not a date
就像陪好友老婆出去玩玩
It's just like if you were going to take your buddy's wife to a movie or something
大家开开心罢了
It's just good company, that's all
这不算约会 绝对不算
It's not a date  It's definitely not a date
小崽子们 你们好吗?
Hey, kids  How you boys doing?
嘿…放轻松点
Hey, keep chilling
知道我们是谁吗?
You know who we are?
我们是你们的合伙人马塞勒斯·华莱士的朋友
We're associates of your business partner Marsellus Wallace
你们一定记得你们的合伙人 对吗?
You do remember your business partner, don't you?
让我来猜猜看
Let me take a wild guess here
你是布莱特?
You're Brett, right?
是的  我就知道
Yeah  I thought so
记得你合伙人马瑟勒斯·华莱士吗？布莱特?
You remember your business partner Marsellus Wallace don't you, Brett?
嗯…记…记得
Yeah, I remember him
很好 看来我和文森特打扰你们吃早餐了
Good  Looks like me and Vincent caught you boys at breakfast
真抱歉
Sorry about that
你们在吃什么?
What you having?
汉堡  汉堡?
Hamburgers  Hamburgers!
营养丰富的早餐哦！
The cornerstone of any nutritious breakfast
哪种汉堡?
What kind of hamburgers?
吉…吉士汉堡…
Ch-ch-cheeseburgers
不不不 我问你哪买的? 麦当劳？温蒂？杰克盒子？
No, no, no, no  Where'd you get 'em? McDonald's, Wendy's, Jack-in-the-Box, where?
大魔法师汉堡
Um, Big Kahuna Burger
大魔法师汉堡！那家夏威夷汉堡店
Big Kahuna Burger  That's that Hawaiian burger joint
我没试过 听说很棒 好吃吗?
I hear they got some tasty burgers  I ain't never had one myself  How are they?
好吃      介意我尝尝你的吗?
They're good  You mind if I try one of yours?
这是你的吧?  是的…
This is yours here, right? Yeah
嗯！这汉堡真棒！
Mmm! This is a tasty burger
文森 你吃过大魔法师汉堡吗?
Vincent, you ever had a Big Kahuna Burger?
尝一口 好吃极了
Want a bite? They're real tasty
我不饿
I ain't hungry
喜欢吃汉堡的人 一定得尝尝这个
If you like burgers, give 'em a try sometime
我…
Me,
我不能经常吃因为我马子是素食主义者
I can't usually get 'em ' cause my girlfriend's a vegetarian
她很想把我也变成素食主义者
which pretty much makes me a vegetarian
不过这汉堡真的很赞!
But I do love the taste of a good burger
知道在法国“吉士汉堡”怎么叫吗?
You know what they call a Quarter-Pounder with Cheese in France?
不知道     告诉他 文森特
No  Tell him, Vincent
皇家吉士堡
Royale with Cheese
知道为什么吗?
You know why they call it that?
因为他们用的是公制?
Because of the metric system?
你真是天才布莱特！
Check out the big brain on Brett!
你真他妈的聪明 公制 一点也不错
You're a smart motherfucker  That's right  The metric system
这是什么?
What's in this?
雪碧  很好
Sprite  Sprite, good
我可以喝一口把汉堡冲下去吗?
You mind if I have some of your tasty beverage to wash this down with?
请便
Go right ahead
过瘾！
That hit the spot
你 睡美人 知道我们为什么来吗？
You, Flock of Seagulls  You know why we're here?
最好告诉我兄弟文森特你们把那东西藏哪儿了?
Why don't you tell my man Vince here where you got the shit hid at?
在那里…     我他妈问你了吗？
It's over there  I don't remember asking you a goddamn thing!
你刚说什么?
You were saying?
在橱柜里
It's in the cupboard
不 你膝盖边的那个
N-no  The one by your kn-knees
满意吗？
We happy?
文森特？
Vincent?
满意吗?
We happy?
很满意
Yeah, we happy  Pbbbt
抱歉 我不知道你的名字
Look    I'm sorry, uh, l   I didn't get your name
你叫文森特 对吧? 但你呢?
I got yours  Uh, Vincent, right? But    but l    I never got yours
我叫皮特 你别想从中脱身
（皮特 pitt,音同pit,pit有凹陷 深渊的意思）
My name's Pitt and your ass ain't talking your way out of this shit
我只想让你们了解…
I just want you to know how
我想让你们知道我们有多后悔
I just want you to know how sorry we are
这事儿搞得我们和华莱士先生都很麻烦
that things got so fucked up with us and and Mr Wallace
不过 我们的初衷是美好的…
W-we got into this thing with the best intentions  I never
抱歉 我打断你讲话了吗?
Oh, I'm sorry  Did I break your concentration?
我不是故意的 请继续
I didn't mean to do that  Please, continue
你刚刚说到“美好的初衷”
You were saying something about  best intentions
怎么? 噢你说完了?
What's the matter? Oh, y-you were finished?
轮到我来反驳了
Oh, well, allow me to retort
马瑟勒斯·华莱士长什么样子?
What does Marsellus Wallace look like?
什么?
What?
你是哪国人?
What country are you from?
什么? 什么?
Wh-what?
我不知道有叫"什么"的国家? 他们讲英文吗?
Why no country I ever heard of, they speak English in What?
说英文 狗杂种 你会说英文吗?   会！
English, motherfucker! Do you speak it? Yes!
那你能听懂我的话吗?
Then you know what I'm saying
描述一下马瑟勒斯·华莱士长什么样子?
Describe what Marsellus Wallace looks like!
什么? 我…
What? I
再说一遍“什么” 再给我说一遍！
Say "what" again! Say "what" again!
你他妈的胆敢再说一遍“什么”试试!
I dare you! I double-dare you, motherfucker! Say "what" one more goddamn time!
他…他…是黑人       还有呢?
H-h-he's black  Go on!
他…是…秃子
He's bald
他像个婊子吗?
Does he look like a bitch?
什么?
What?
他像个婊子吗?
Does he look like a bitch?
不！
No!
你为什么想像操婊子一样操他?        我没有！
Then why you try to fuck him like a bitch, Brett? I didn't
是的你有 你有！布莱特 你想操他！
Yes, you did  Yes, you did, Brett! You tried to fuck him
除了她老婆马瑟勒斯·华莱士不喜欢被任何人操！
Marsellus Wallace don't like to be fucked by anybody except Mrs  Wallace
读过圣经吗?
You read the Bible, Brett?
读过
Y-yes
有段圣经现在读应该很合适
Well, there's this passage I got memorized
《以西结书》二十五章十七节
（以西结是书的作者 该书属于先知书 记载在《圣经·旧约》）
sort of fits this occasion  Ezekiel 25:17
正直之人的道路
The path of the righteous man
被小人的自私贪婪和恶人的暴虐专政所笼罩
is beset on all sides by the inequities of the selfish and the tyranny of evil men
以仁慈善良之名引领弱小穿越黑暗之谷的“牧羊人”
Blessed is he who in the name of charity and good will
必将得到神的护佑
shepherds the weak through the Valley of Darkness
因为他守护兄弟同胞 拯救迷途羔羊
for he is truly his brother's keeper and the finder of lost children
我将对那些毒害和屠杀我同胞的人
And I will strike down upon thee with great vengeance and furious anger
充满巨大的仇恨和爆裂的怒火！
those who attempt to poison and destroy My brothers
当我复仇之焰吞噬你的那刻 你会知道我的名字 叫做上帝！
And you will know My name is the Lord when I lay My vengeance upon thee!
(文森特与马瑟勒斯之妻)
你会发现…
I think you're gonna find
在这一切结束之后……
when all this shit is over and done
你他妈的会发现自己非常满足
I think you're gonna find yourself one smilin' motherfucker
事情是这样的布奇……
Thing is, Butch,
你现在还很能打
right now you got ability
但可悲的是…
But painful as it may be
你不可能永远打下去
ability don't last
你的日子就要到头了
And your days are just about over
现实是他妈的非常残酷的
Now, that's a hard motherfuckin' fact of life but that's a fact of life
这点你必须清楚
your ass is gonna have to get realistic about
瞧 这圈子里充满了不知天高地厚的杂种
See, this business is filled to the brim with unrealistic motherfuckers
这些傻逼还以为他们会像酒一样越老越吃香
motherfuckers who thought their ass would age like wine
他们会越来越老吗？会的
If you mean it turns to vinegar, it does
他们会越来越强吗？不会！
If you mean it gets better with age, it don't
而且 布奇…
Besides, Butch
你还能再打几场拳赛?
how many fights you think you got in you, anyway?
两场?
Hmm? Two?
拳击手是没有“老人节”的
Boxers don't have an Old-timer's Day
你曾经很接近 但你没有成名
You came close, but you never made it
如果你能成名你早就成名了
And if you were gonna make it You would have made it before now
你是我好兄弟吗?
You my nigger?
应该是吧
It certainly appears so
拳赛当晚 你会有点不爽……
Night of the fight, you may feel a slight sting
那是自尊在搞鬼
That's pride fucking with you
去他的自尊!
Fuck pride!
自尊只会伤人… 不能帮人
Pride only hurts  It never helps
你得克服这鬼东西！
You fight through that shit
一年后 你在加勒比海滩玩水的时候
Cause a year from now when you're kickin' it in the Caribbean
你一定会对自己说：“马瑟勒斯是对的”
you're gonna say to yourself, Marsellus Wallace was right
没问题 华莱士先生
I got no problem with that, Mr  Wallace
第五回合 你会被撂倒
In the fifth, your ass goes down
说一遍
Say it
第五回合 我会被撂倒
In the fifth, my ass goes down
哟 阿姆斯特丹的文森特 英格尔伍德的朱尔斯 快滚进来！
Yo, Vincent Vega, our man in Amsterdam  Jules Winnfield, our man in Inglewood  Get your asses on in here!
我勒个去 你们的衣服是怎么搞的？
Goddamn, nigger! What's up with them clothes?
你不会想知道的
You don't even want to know
老大呢?
Where's the big man?
老大在那边谈事情
Big man's right over there taking care of some business
先休息一下
Why don't you hang back for a second or two, you know?
等那白人走了 你们就过去
You see the white boy leave, just go on over
你怎么样?
How you been?
我非常好 你呢?
I've been doing pretty good  How 'bout yourself?
很好
All right
听说你要带米娅出去玩？
So, I hear you're taking Mia out tomorrow?
是马瑟勒斯吩咐的
At Marsellus' request
你见过她吗?    还没
Have you met Mia? Not yet
什么他妈的这么好笑啊?
What's so fucking funny?
没什么 我去尿尿
Not a goddamn thing  I got to piss
我不是一个他妈的白痴好吗?
Look, I'm not a fucking idiot, all right?
他是老大的女人 我只是坐在她对面
It's the big man's wife  I'm gonna sit across from her
低头吃东西,听她讲笑话,然后笑,就这些
chew my food with my mouth closed laugh at her fucking jokes, and that's it
嘿 我可没想插手你们之间这些破事儿
Hey, my name's Paul, and this shit's between y'all
那你问那么多干嘛?傻逼！
Then what did you fucking ask me about it for?Asshole！
来包红苹果香烟
Pick a pack of red apples.
带过滤嘴的吗?      不
Filters? Nah
有什么好看的 朋友？
You looking at something, friend?
我不是你朋友 傻逼
You ain't my friend, palooka
你说什么？
What was that?
你听得很清楚了 秃子
I think you heard me just fine, punchy
文森特来了? 好兄弟到这儿来
Vincent Vega's in the house? My nigger  Get your ass over here
香烟一块四毛
Pack of Red Apples  $ 1 40
再来盒火柴
And some matches
会让你全身每个地方都爽的……
It's as if it turns every part of your body into the tip of a penis
那本刺洞的书棒呆了！我借你
I'll lend it to you  It's a great book on piercing
你看到他们怎么用那枪来给你穿耳洞吗?
Well, you see how they use that gun to pierce your ears?
给你乳头穿孔时不会也用的那枪吧?
They don't use that to pierce your nipples, too, do they?
别提那枪了！穿孔的美妙感觉全让它给破坏了
Forget that gun  That gun goes against the entire idea behind piercing
我身上十八个洞都用针穿的
All my piercing, eighteen places on my body every one of 'em done with a needle
耳朵各五个、左边乳头一个、
Five in each ear  One through the nipple of my left breast
右鼻孔两个、左眉一个、
Two in my right nostril  One in my left eyebrow
肚皮、嘴唇、阴蒂各一个 舌头上还有个穿扣
One in my belly  One in my lip  One in my clit  And I wear a stud in my tongue
借问一下…
Excuse me
只是好奇…
I was just curious, but, um
干嘛要穿个穿扣在舌头上？
why would you wear a stud in your tongue?
性玩具 有助于口交
It's a sex thing  Helps fellatio
文森（西班牙语）,到我房间来
Vincenzo  Step into my office
这些叫“熊猫” 墨西哥的 非常棒
This is Panda, from Mexico  Very good stuff
这种“巴法”有点不同 但也很正点
Now, that's Bava  Different, but equally good
那种叫“朱古力” 是德国哈特兹山出产的
And that is Choco, from the Hartz Mountains of Germany
前两种每克三百 友情价
Now, the first two are the same 300 a gram  Those are friend prices
这种贵点 一克五百块
But this one is a little more expensive  This is 500 a gram
不过你要是来上一针 就知道它贵哪儿了
but when you shoot it you will know where that extra money went
前两种货没问题 绝对是真正的上等货
Now, there's nothing wrong with these two.This is real, real, real good shit
可是这种会让你爽疯掉的！
But this one is a fucking madman
别忘了 我可是刚从阿姆斯特丹回来的
Remember, I just got back from Amsterdam
我们在英格尔伍德吗？不 你在我家里
Are we in Inglewood? No  You're in my home
分得出好坏的那些白人 就只认我家的货！
Now, white people who know the difference between good shit and bad shit, this is the house they come to
我他要和阿姆斯特丹的狗屎货进行“百事挑战”！
（当时百事可乐针对其他饮料推出的一项活动）
Now, my shit, I'll take the Pepsi Challenge with that Amsterdam shit
这周随便哪天都行
any old day of the fucking week
这可是个大胆的宣言！
That's a bold statement
这儿不是阿姆斯特丹文森 这里是卖方市场
This ain't Amsterdam, Vince  This is a seller's market
可卡因不流行了因为……不流行了
Coke is fucking dead as    dead
海洛因又要卷土重来了
Heroin is coming back in a big fucking way
好吧 那就给我三克会爽疯的
All right, give me three grams of madman
如果有你说的这么好 我会再来买一千块的
If it's as good as you say it is I'll come back and buy another thousand
嗯 希望还有剩
Well, I just hope that I still have some left for you
不过 我会给你一些我的私房货
But I'm giving you some out of my own private stash
用袋子装 好吗?
Hey, I'm out of balloons  Is a baggie all right?
没问题
Yeah, that's cool
好的 我马上给你拿一个来
All right  I'll just get one for you
甜心 请拿些袋子和 呃 胶条 给我好吗?在厨房里
Honey, will you get me some baggies and, uh, twistix from the kitchen?
嘿 你觉得朱蒂如何? 她没有男朋友 想和她玩玩吗?
Hey, uh, what do you think about Trudi? She ain't got a boyfriend  You want to, uh, hang out, get high?
谁是朱蒂? 脸上都是洞的那个?
Which one is Trudi? The one with all the shit in her face
不 那是乔蒂 我老婆
No, that's Jody  That's my wife
对不起老兄 谢谢
I'm sorry, man  Thank you
不行 我还有事
No, I can't  Um, I gotta be someplace
好吧 随你便
All right  No problemo
改天再说吧
I'll take a rain check
要说：“谢谢你乔蒂！”
Thank you, Jody
还在开你的迈锐宝?
Still got your Malibu?
噢！你知道那天有个混蛋做了什么？
Ah, man  You know what some fucker did the other day?
怎么了?
What?
他妈的用钥匙给刮花了！
Fucking keyed it
噢！老兄 真是糟透了
Oh, man, that's fucked up
我停在车库三年
Talking about it,I had it in storage for 3 years
才开出来五天 就被个狗日的混蛋刮了！
It was out 5 days and some dickless piece of shit fucked with it
应该毙了他
They should be fucking killed, man
不用审判 就地正法
No trial, no jury, straight to execution
我真想当场逮到这个混蛋
Boy, I wish I could've caught him doing it
不论付出什么代价 都要抓到这个混蛋
I'd have given anything to catch that asshole doing it
被我抓到他就知道有多后悔了！
It'a been worth him doing it just so I could've caught him doing it
真是浑蛋
What a fucker!
有什么能比刮别人车更卑鄙的了？
What's more chicken shit than fucking with a man's automobile?
简直不上道嘛
It's just against the rules
谢谢
Thank you
谢谢你 介意我在这儿来上一针吗?
Thank you  Mind if I shoot up here?
我的家,你的家（西班牙语）
Mi casa, su casa
非常感谢！（西班牙语）
Muchas gracias
嗨文森特 我在换衣服 门没锁
进来弄杯酒喝  ——米娅
喂?
Hello?
文森特
文森特…
Vincent
用对讲机
I'm on the intercom
对讲机在哪?
Where is it? Where is the intercom?
两个非洲雕像旁边墙上
It's on the wall by the two African fellows
在你右手边
To your right
接近…接近…中奖
Warm  Warmer  Disco
喂?
Hello
要讲话就按钮
Push the button if you want to talk
喂?
Hello
去弄杯酒喝 我马上下来
Go make yourself a drink and I'll be down in two shakes of a lamb's tail
酒在壁炉旁边
The bar is by the fireplace
收到
OK
注：台词"Warm,Warmer,Disco."出自电影Saturday Night Fever (1977) （周末夜狂热）
文森特扮演者约翰·特拉沃尔塔出演了本片并展示了精彩舞姿
约翰·特拉沃尔塔堪称70年代巨星舞王 80年代被打入冷宫后隐退
17年后凭借本片再次以新人身份入主好莱坞 从此东山再起
我们走
Let's go
这是什么鬼地方?
What the fuck is this place?
杰克兔斯利姆餐厅 猫王的粉丝都爱来
This is Jack Rabbit Slim's  An Elvis man should love it
不如去牛排馆
Come on, Mia, let's go get a steak
这里也有牛排 别这么死板
You can get a steak here, daddy-o
你先请 小猫咪
Oh, after you, kitty cat
小姐先生 晚上好 能效劳吗?
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen  Now, how may I help you?
我订了位子 华莱士
There's a reservation under Wallace
华莱士?
Wallace?
我订了一辆车
We reserved a car
请他们坐那里 克莱斯勒
Oh, a car  Why don't you seat them in the Chrysler?
瑞奇尼尔逊 请掌声鼓励
Let's hear it for Ricky Nelson! Fantastic job, Rick  Thank you very much
文森特！
Vincent!
他下半场会再回来为大家表演
Just so that you all know Ricky will be back in the second half of our show
希望各位用餐愉快 谢谢大家！
So we hope you enjoy your meals here at Jack Rabbit Slim's
谁…要…香…烟?
Phillip    Morris!
觉得怎么样?
What do you think?
像活的腊像馆
I think it's like a wax museum with a pulse
我是巴迪 要点些什么?（Buddy Holly 巴迪·霍利
美国50年代流行音乐偶像 另外本片客串巴迪的是好莱坞配角狂人史蒂夫·布西密）
Hi, I'm Buddy  What can I get you?
牛排…牛排…
Let's see  Steak, steak, steak
我就点道格拉斯牛排
Yeah, the Douglas Sirk steak  I'll have that
几分熟?要烤焦还是血淋淋
How do you want that cooked? Burnt to a crisp, or bloody as hell?
血淋淋 你看 有香草可乐
Bloody as hell, and oh, yeah, look at this  Vanilla Coke
你呢 佩吉·苏?
（Peggy Sue 佩吉·苏 是巴迪·霍利的经典曲目）
What about you, Peggy Sue?
我点…达尔伍德柯比汉堡
I'll have the Durwood Kirby burger
血淋淋的
bloody
还有…
and
五块钱的奶昔
the $5 00 shake
什么口味 香草还是巧克力?
How do you want that shake? Martin and Lewis, or Amos and Andy?
香草
Martin and Lewis
奶昔要五块钱?
Did you just order a $5 00 shake?
没错
Mm-hmm
只是牛奶加冰淇淋?
That's a shake  That's milk and ice cream
应该没错
Last I heard
这要五块钱?
That's $5 00?
没放酒或加料?
You don't put bourbon in it or nothin'?
没有
No
只是好奇
Just checkin'
我马上把饮料拿来
I'll be right back with your drinks
可以替我卷一根吗牛仔?
（约翰·特拉沃尔塔主演了电影都市牛郎 Urban Cowboy (1980)）
Could you, um roll me one of those, cowboy?
这根给你 女牛仔
（乌玛·瑟曼主演了电影蓝调女牛仔 Even Cowgirls Get the Blues (1993)）
You can have this one, cowgirl
谢谢
Thanks
别客气
Think nothin' of it
马瑟勒斯说你刚从阿姆斯特丹回来
So    Marsellus said you just got back from Amsterdam
没错  在那待了多久?
Sure did  How long were you there?
三年多
Just over three years
我每年都去那里休息一个月
I go there about once a year to chill out for a month
真的?这我倒不知道
No kiddin'? I didn't know that
你为什么要知道
Why would you?
听说你演过样片儿?
I heard you did a pilot
那是我的十五分钟
That was my fifteen minutes
那是什么?
What was it?
霹雳五狐 讲女特工的电视
It was a show about a team of female secret agents called  Fox Force Five
什么?  霹雳五狐？
What? Fox Force Five
狐狸 是指我们像狐狸一样狡猾聪明
Fox, as in we're a bunch of foxy chicks
霹雳表示我们的力量不可忽视
Force, as in we're a force to be reckoned with
五是因为有一、二、三、四、五个人
And Five, as in there's one, two, three, four, five of us
金发的叫萨摩希特奥尼尔 她是队长
There was a blond one    Sommerset O'Neal  She was the leader
日本狐是功夫大师
The Japanese Fox was a kung-fu master
黑妞是爆破专家
The black girl was a demolition expert
法国妞的特长是风骚
French Fox's speciality was sex
那你擅长什么?
What was your specialty?
飞刀
Knives
我的角色叫乌鸦麦考伊 从小在马戏团长大
Character I played, Raven McCoy her background was she grew up raised by circus performers
世上最致命的飞刀高手
she was the deadliest woman in the world with a knife
另外 她会说的老笑话数不胜数
and she knew a zillion old jokes
因为她爷爷 一个老杂耍艺人教她的
Her grandfather, an old vaudevillian, taught her
要是我们被选中的话会有一个噱头
And if we would've got picked up they would've worked in a gimmick
每集我都会说个笑话
where every show I would've told another joke
里面所有的老笑话你都会说?
You know any of them old jokes?
我只说过一个 因为节目只拍了一集
Well, I only got the chance to say one  cause we only did one show
说来听听        已经过时了
Tell me  It's corny
别担心 说吧
Don't be that way  Tell me
你不会喜欢的 我会很尴尬
No  You wouldn't like it, and I'd be embarrassed
你可以对五千万观众说 却不肯对我说?
You'd be em You told 50 million people, and you can't tell me?
我答应不笑
I promise I won't laugh
我就怕你不笑 文森
That's what I'm afraid of, Vince
我不是这个意思 你知道的
That's not what I meant, and you know it
我现在肯定不会说 因为期望被抬得太高了
Well, now I'm definitely not gonna tell you cause it's been built up too much
还卖关子啊！
What a gyp
香草奶昔
Martin and Lewis
香草可乐
Vanilla Coke
嗯 好喝！   我可以尝尝吗?
Mmm  Yummy  You think I could have a sip of that?
请便
Be my guest
我得尝尝五块一杯的奶昔是什么味道
I gotta know what a $5 00 shake tastes like
用我的 别怕 我没病
You can use my straw  I don't have cooties
搞不好我有
Yeah, but maybe I do
我才不怕
Cooties, I can handle
好吧
All right
妈的 这奶昔棒透了！
Goddamn, that's a pretty fuckin' good milk shake
是吧!
Told you
我不知道值不值五块 但是实在好喝！
I don't know if it was worth $5 00 but it was pretty fucking good
真讨厌
Don't you hate that?
讨厌什么?
Hate what?
尴尬的沉默
Uncomfortable silences
为什么我们必须要唠叨些屁话才会感觉舒服点?
Why do we feel it's necessary to yak about bullshit in order to be comfortable?
问的好 我不知道
I don't know, but it's a good question
只有当你找到一个真正特别的人时
That's when you know you've found somebody really special
才能闭嘴享受片刻的沉默
when you can just shut the fuck up for a minute and comfortably share a silence
我不认为我们到了那个程度 不过别担心 我们才刚认识
Well, I don't think we're quite there yet but don't feel bad  We just met each other
这样好了…
I'll tell you what
我去厕所补补妆
I'm going to go to the bathroom and powder my nose
你好好想要说什么
You sit here and think of something to say
我会的
I'll do that
好的
OK
我说该死啊,该死的…
(这其实是电影Easy Rider (1969)(逍遥骑士)片头曲《The Pusher》的歌词“I said goddamn! Goddamn...”)
I said goddamn! Goddamn
嗯……去一趟厕所 菜就上了 真幸福！
Mmm  Don't you just love it when you come back from the bathroom to find your food waiting for you?
很幸运我们的菜都上齐了 我觉得“巴迪·霍利”的服务不怎样
We're lucky we got anything at all I don't think Buddy Holly's much of a waiter
我们应该坐“玛丽莲·梦露”的桌子
Maybe we should've sat in Marilyn Monroe's section
哪一个?这有两个梦露
Which one? There's two Monroes
才没有
No, there's not
那是玛丽莲·梦露
That is Marilyn Monroe
那是玛米·范多伦
... and that's Mamie Van Doren
我没看见简·曼斯菲尔德她可能今晚休班或是其他什么
（以上三位都是五十年代的性感尤物代表）
And I don't see Jayne Mansfield  She must have the night off or somethin'
挺在行嘛！
Pretty smart
我也风光过（舞王这句台词真是意味深长啊……）
Yeah, I got my moments
想到要说什么吗?
So, did you think of somethin' to say?
实际上 想到了
Actually, I did
不过…
However
你人还不错 我不想冒犯你
You seem like a really nice person and I don't want to offend you
呜！这可不像是盲目无聊的客套话
Ooh  This doesn't sound like the usual mindless, boring gettin'-to-know-you chitchat
你好像真有话要说
That sounds like you actually have somethin' to say
好吧 没错 没错
Well, well, I do  I do
不过你得保证不能生气
But you have to promise not to be offended
不不不不！
No! No, no, no
我不能做保证
You can't promise somethin' like that
我又不知道你要问什么
I have no idea what you're gonna ask me
我的本能反应可能会生气
and my natural response could be to get offended
所以我不能保证不生气
I would've broken my promise
那就忘了它吧
Let's just forget it
不可能的试图忘记任何有趣的事情都是徒劳的
That's an impossibilityTrying to forget anything as intriguing as this would be an exercise in futility
是吗?
Is that a fact?
况且 没我允许 问起来会更刺激
Besides, isn't it more exciting when you don't have permission?
好吧 好吧 我就问了
All right  All right  Well, here it goes
安特万是怎么回事?
What did you, uh, think about what happened to Antwan?
谁?      “恐怖东尼” 你认识他
Who's Antwan? Tony Rocky Horror  You know him
他从窗台摔下去了
He fell out of a window
嗯 没错 有这种说法 但是另一种说法是他“被”摔下去了
Mmm  Mmm  Well, that is one way to say it  Another way to say it would be that he was thrown out
这种说法还说是马瑟勒斯干的
Another way would be was he was thrown out by Marsellus
甚至说马瑟勒斯把他扔下窗台是因为你
and yet even another way is to say he was thrown of a window by Marsellus because of you
真的吗?
Is that a fact?
不 我只是听说而已
No, no  It's not a fact  It's just what I heard
听谁说的?
Who told you?
他们
They
他们还真是八卦
They talk a lot, don't they?
确实八卦 确实八卦
They certainly do  They certainly do
别害羞 文森特 他们还说了什么?
Don't be shy, Vincent  What else did they say?
我不是害羞…呃……
Well, I'm not    I'm not shy  Um
有没有涉及到“F”开头的词?
Did it involve the F word?
没有 没有……
No  No, no, no
他们只说安特万替你做脚部按摩
They just said that Antwan had given you a foot massage
还有呢?
And?
没啦 没有了
And    and nothin'  That's it
你听说马瑟勒斯把“恐怖东尼”从四楼窗台扔下去
You heard Marsellus threw Tony Rocky Horror out of a four-story window
就因为他给我做了脚部按摩？
for giving me a foot massage?
对  那你相信吗?
Mm-hmm  And you believe that?
听起来似乎有可能
Well, I mean at the time I was told, it sounded reasonable
马瑟勒斯把东尼从四楼窗台扔下去
Marsellus throwing Tony out of a four-story window
就因为他按摩了我的脚 这合理吗?
for massaging my feet seemed reasonable?
是有点过 但并不是不可能 我懂的
No, it seemed excessive but that doesn't mean it didn't happen  I mean, I understand
我知道马瑟勒斯非常非常爱护你
that Marsellus is very, very protective of you
丈夫爱护老婆是一件事
A husband being protective of his wife is one thing
老婆被人碰了脚就要杀人是另一回事
A husband almost killing another man for touching his wife's feet is something else
不是这样吗?
But did it happen?
安特万唯一一次碰我 是握我的手…在我的婚礼上
Only thing Antwan ever touched of mine was my hand when he shook it…at my wedding
真的?
Really?
没人知道为什么马瑟勒斯要把东尼从四楼窗台扔出去除了他们自己
Truth is, nobody knows why Marsellus threw Tony out of that four-story window except Marsellus and Tony
但是你们这群小流氓比妇女缝纫小组还三八！
But when you little scamps get together you're worse than a sewing circle
女士们、先生们……
Ladies and gentlemen
各位期待已久的……
now the moment you've all been waiting for
杰克兔斯利姆餐厅扭扭舞大赛
the world-famous Jack Rabbit Slim's Twist Contest
优胜者可获得梦露手上的奖杯
This is where one lucky couple will win this handsome trophy that Marilyn here is holding
谁愿意首先上台?
Now, who'll be our first contestants?
我！
Right here!
我想跳舞
I wanna dance
不不不……
No, no, no, no, no, no, no
No, no, no, no, no, no
我确信马瑟勒斯…我老公 你老大
I do believe Marsellus    my husband, your boss
要你陪我出来 让我随心所欲
told you to take me out and do whatever I wanted
现在我想跳舞 我要赢 我要那座奖杯
Now I want to dance  I want to win  I want that trophy,
给我好好地跳  好吧
so dance goodAll right  You asked for it
我们来看看第一对挑战者
Let's hear it for our first contestants
让我们认识下他们 小姐贵姓?
Let's meet our first contestants here this evening  Young lady, what is your name?
米亚马瑟勒斯夫人
Mrs  Mia Wallace
你的舞伴?
And how about your fella here?
文森特维加
Vincent Vega
就看你们表现吧 加油！
All right  Let's see what you can do  Take it away!
这算不算尴尬的沉默?
Is that what you call an uncomfortable silence?
我不知道这算什么
I don't know what you call that
准备喝的 来点音乐
Drinks  Music
我要去小便
I'm gonna take a piss
不必告诉我文森 尽管去吧
That's a little bit more information than I needed, Vince, but go right ahead
只喝一杯就够了……
One drink and that's it
别冲动 快点喝
Don't be rude  Drink your drink  But do it quickly
道声晚安就赶快走人
Say good night and go home
你得搞清楚… 这是在考验你的忠诚度
You see, this is a moral test of oneself  Whether or not you can maintain loyalty
因为忠诚非常重要
Because being loyal is very important
记得 出去跟她说晚安 今晚你玩得很愉快
So, you're gonna go out there, you're gonna say Good night  I've had a very lovely evening
走出大门上车
Walk out the door and get in the car
然后回家乖乖打手枪 你需要做的就是这些
Go home, jerk off, and that's all you're gonna do
好了 米娅 我得先走了 好吗?
All right, Mia  So, listen, I gotta go  All right?
噢 我的老天爷!
Oh, Jesus fucking Christ
完了！完了!
Oh, fuck me! Fuck me!
来 我们走 快走
Oh, come on, girl  We're gettin' out of here  We gotta walk now
别在我手上死了 米娅 小白痴！
Don't fucking die on me, Mia  Silly fuck
接电话!
Answer!
操你妈兰斯 接电话呀！
Fuck you, Lance! Answer!
兰斯 烂电话在响!
Lance! The goddamn phone's ringing!
我听到了
I can hear it
我以为你告诉过这些混蛋不要这么晚打来！
I thought you told those fuckin' assholes never to call here this late
没错 我说过 这也正是我现在要跟这个混蛋说的
Yeah, I told 'em and that is exactly what I'm going to tell this fucking asshole right now
兰斯 麻烦大了！我就过来
Lance, Vincent  I'm in big fuckin' trouble, man  I'm comin' to your house
等等…不要着急 是什么麻烦?
Whoa, whoa  Hold your horses, man  Wh-what's the problem?
我手上这婆娘嗑错药快挂了！
I got this chick, she's fuckin' O D  Ing on me
别带她来 我他妈没有跟你开玩笑伙计！
Don't bring her here  I'm not even fucking joking with you, man
别带该死的小鬼到我家来！
Don't not be bringing some fucked-up pooh-butt to my house
我没办法
No choice
她嗑错药了?
She's O D  In'?
就快挂了！
She's fuckin' dyin' on me, man!
这是你惹出来的 你该带她去医院 再找个律师
OK, well, then you bite the fuckin' bullet and you take her to a hospital and call a lawyer
没门儿！
Negative
这不是我的问题 伙计 你搞的她 他他妈的处理这事！
This is not my fuckin' problem, man! You fucked her up, you fuckin' deal with this!
你用的是大哥大吗?
Are you talking to me on a cellular phone?
我不认识你 你是谁？别过来 我要挂断了 挂了！
I don't know you  Who is this? Don't come here  I'm hanging up the phone  Prank caller! Prank caller!
搞什么鬼?
What the hell was that?!
你他妈的疯了吗?
Have you lost your fucking mind?
别用大哥大讲吸毒
You were talking about drug shit on a cellular ph Lance, help me
你他妈还撞到我的房子!
You crashed your car into my fuckin' house!
嘿！嘿？你聋啦? 别带个死婊子到我家！
Hey, hey, hey! Are you deaf? You are not bringing this fucked-up bitch into my house!
这死婊子是马瑟勒斯华莱士的老婆 知道马瑟勒斯·华莱士是谁吗？
This fucked-up bitch is Marsellus Wallace's wife  Do you know who Marsellus Wallace is?
听过      如果她在我手上挂了 我他妈就死定了！
Yeah  If she croaks on me, I'm a fucking grease spot!
我他妈只好跟他说你不肯帮忙
I will be forced to tell him that you did not help
还他妈让她死在你门口 好 来 帮帮忙
and that you let her die on your fuckin' lawn  Now, come on, help me  Help me  Pick her up
操！
Shit!
兰斯！
Lance!
现在是该死的凌晨1：30 这他妈是在搞什么鬼?
It's 1:30 in the goddamn morning  What the fuck's going on out here?
她是谁?
Who's she?
从冰箱把肾上素和针筒拿来
Go to the fridge and get the adrenaline shot
她怎么了?
What's wrong with her?
嗑错药！ 把她赶出去！
She's O D  Ing! Get her out of here!
快去呀！
Get the shot!
操你妈！  也操你！
Fuck you! Fuck you, too!
臭婊子！
What a fuckin' bitch
跟她说话 她去拿针 我去拿医学指南
Just keep talkin' to her  She's gettin' the shot  I'm gonna go get my little black medical book
你他妈要医学指南干嘛?
What the fuck you need a medical book for?
我又没替人打过肾上腺素针
I never had to give an adrenaline shot before
你从没给人打过肾上腺素针?
You've never given an adrenaline shot?
我没有！我不跟这种傻逼一起嗑药 我朋友都很有经验
I never had to！I don't go joypopping with a bunch of bubblegummers  My friends can handle their highs
快去拿针！
Get the shot!
我正在拿 如果你同意！
I am if you'll let me
我他妈没阻止你！     别跟我说话！快跟她说话!
I ain't fucking stopping you! Well, stop talkin' to me  Start talkin' to her!
快去拿针！        好啦！
Get the shot! All right!
快点兰斯 我们要失去她了！
Hurry up, Lance! We're losin' her!
我已经是最快了！
I'm lookin' as fast as I can!
他在找什么?
What's he lookin' for?
我不知道 一本书
I don't know  Some book
你在找什么?
What are you lookin' for?
我的医学指南
My little black medical book!
你在找什么?
What are you lookin' for?
他妈的医学指南！就像给护士用的教科书！
A little black fuckin' medical book! It's like a textbook they give to nurses
我从没看到过        相信我一定有
I never saw no medical book  Well, trust me, I have one
如果这么重要 干嘛不跟针筒放在一起?
If it's so important, why don't you keep it with the shot?
我不知道！别烦我！
I don't know! Stop bothering me!
等你找到 她也死在地毯上了 这么乱 你永远也找不到的
While you're lookin' for it, she's gonna die on our carpet  You're never gonna find anything in this mess
亲爱的 你如果不闭嘴 我他妈就毙了你滚过去！
Honey, I'm going to fucking kill you if you don't shut up! Get in here!
别他妈的挡我路！
Get the fuck out of my way
猪!
Pig
别他妈吵了！快替她注射！
Quit fuckin' around and give her the shot
脱掉她衣服 找她的心脏
While I'm doin' this  you take off her shirt and find her heart
一定要分毫不差?
It's got to be exact?
没错 针头得直接插进她心脏 所以我猜一定要精准
Yeah, exact  A shot in the heart, so I guess it's gotta be exact
我不确定她心脏在哪 在这儿吗?
I don't know exactly where her heart is  I think it's here
对了 对吗?给我支记号笔
That's it  This it? What I need is a big fat magic marker
懂吗?  什么?
You got it? What?
记号笔！一支该死的黑色记号笔!
A magic marker! A felt pen! A fuckin' black magic marker!
快点！
All right  Hurry up
操！  应该没问题
Fuck  OK, OK, OK  I think it's ready
快点！
Hurry up, man  Hurry up
我告诉你怎么做
I'll tell you what to do
不不不 我不行 你来比较好
No, no, no  You're gonna give her the shot
你来 我不干
You're gonna give her the shot  I ain't givin' her the shot
我没干过也不想干
I ain't givin' her the shot  I never done this before
我也一样
I ain't never done it before, either  I ain't startin' now
你惹的麻烦自己解决
You brought her here, that means you're gonna give her the shot
如果是我带个嗑错药的婊子来 才应该我给她注射！
The day I bring an O D  Ing bitch to your house then I give her the shot  Give her the shot
拿来 拿来
Give it to me  Here  Give me that
告诉我怎么做
Tell me what to do
你得直接插入心脏
OK  You're giving her an injection of adrenaline straight to her heart, but she's got a breastplate
她隆过胸 你得插深点
You've got to pierce through that
你得快速地刺下去
You gotta bring the needle down in a stabbing motion
我得刺三次吗?
I gotta stab her three times?
蠢蛋！一次就够了！
No! You don't gotta stab her three times  Just once
不过你得用力刺穿她的假奶
But hard enough to get through her breastplate into her heart
然后按下针筒
Once you do that, you press down on the plunger
然后会怎样?
OK, then what happens?
我也很想知道
I'm kind of curious about that myself
别他妈开玩笑伙计！我会害死她吗?
This ain't no fuckin' joke, man! Am I gonna kill her?
她应该会马上醒来
She's supposed to come out of it like that
好吧 数到三
All right  Count to three
好了吗? 一
Ready? One
二…
two
三!
Three!
如果你没事就说点什么
If you're all right, then say something
“点什么”?
Something
他妈的酷毙了
Ha ha  That was fuckin' trippy  Ha ha ha ha
米娅…
Mia  Mia
你觉得该怎样处理此事?
what's your thoughts on    on on how to handle this?
你觉得呢?
What's yours?
我的意见是马瑟勒斯的整个一生
Well, I'm of the opinion that if Marsellus lived his whole life
都没有必要知道今天的事
he don't need to know nothin' about this incident
要是他知道 我也会和你一样有麻烦
If Marsellus knew about this incident I'd be in as much trouble as you
我看不见得
I seriously doubt that
你不说 我也不会讲
I can keep a secret if you can
握个手？
Shake on it?
一言为定
Mum's the word?
如果你不怪罪我 那我得回家犯心脏病去了
Now, if you'll excuse me I'm gonna go home and have a heart attack
文森特！想听我的霹雳五狐笑话吗?
Vincent! Do you want to hear my Fox Force Five joke?
想… 不过我吓傻了 怕是笑不出来了
Sure  Except that I think I'm still a little too petrified to laugh
不 你不笑是因为根本不好笑
No, you won't laugh 'cause it's not funny
不过如果你还是想听  我就说
But if you still wanna hear it, I'll tell it
我很想听    好吧
I can't wait  OK
一家蕃茄三口走在路上
Three tomatoes are walking down the street Papa Tomato, Mama Tomato, and Baby Tomato
小蕃茄走太慢 老蕃茄就发飙了
Baby Tomato starts lagging behind and Papa Tomato gets really angry
老蕃茄转过头来说… 快跟上(音同"蕃茄酱")
and Papa Tomato gets really angry goes back and squishes him, and says, Catch up
蕃茄酱…
Ketchup
回头见
See you around
笨狗  他以为雕像是活的
Oh, that Paddlefoot. he funny, silly dog He think totem pole alive  Hee hee hee!
真是蠢
He arctic tenderfoot
雕像是永远不会动的
That totem pole been here forever
布奇
Butch?
过来  别看电视了
Butch, stop watching TV a second
干嘛?       有个特别的客人来看你
Yeah? We got a special visitor
记得我说你爸死在俘虏营吗?
Now    do you remember when I told you your daddy died in a P O W  Camp?
这是昆斯上尉   他和你爸被关在一起
Well    this here is Captain Koons  He was in the P O W  Camp with Daddy
嗨   小伙子  我早就听过你了
Hello, little man  Boy, I sure heard a bunch about you
我是你爸爸的好友
See, I was a good friend of your dad's
一起被关在越南五年
We were in that Hanoi pit of hell together over five years
好在你绝不会再去经历这一切
Hopefully you'll never have to experience this yourself
当两个人同甘共苦像我和你爸这么久时
but when two men are in a situation like me and your dad were for as long as we were
那就必然会承担起另一个人所肩负的责任
you take on certain responsibilities of the other
如果是我没能回来…
If it had been me who'd not made it
今天一定是库利奇少校在对我儿子说这番话   吉姆
Major Coolidge would be talkin' right now to my son    Jim
但现实是咱俩在谈话
But the way it turned out I'm talkin' to you
布奇…
Butch
我要给你一样东西
I got somethin' for you
我给你的这块表是你曾祖父在第一次世界大战时买的
This watch I got here was first purchased by your great-grandfather during the First World War
在田纳西诺克斯维尔的小杂货店买的
It was bought in a little general store in Knoxville, Tennessee
这是首批出厂的手表
Made by the first company to ever make wristwatches
当时的人们还在使用怀表
Up till then, people just carried pocket watches
二等步兵厄瑞纳·库利奇从海上出发去巴黎那天买的
It was bought by Private Doughboy Erine Coolidge on the day he set sail for Paris
这就成为那次战争中他不曾离手的战表
This was your great- grandfather's war watch and he wore it every day he was in that war
服完役  他带着这表回老家找你曾祖母
And when he'd done his duty he went home to your great-grandmother took the watch off
把表放在一个旧咖啡罐里 一直放到你祖父戴恩·库利奇
put it in an old coffee can and in that can it stayed Till your gr anddad, Dane Coolidge
又应征入伍 远赴海外再次同德国人作战
was called upon by his country to go overseas and fight the Germans once again
这次是第二次世界大战
This time they called it World War II
你曾祖父把表交给你祖父当作吉祥物
Your great-grandfather gave this watch to your granddad for good luck
不幸的是 戴恩没他老爸幸运
Unfortunately, Dane's luck wasn't as good as his old man's
他所在的海军陆战队在威克岛一役中全体阵亡
Dane was a marine, and he was killed along with all the other marines at the Battle of Wake Island
你祖父知道自己面临死亡
Your granddad was facing death  He knew it
所有的陆战小伙们对活着离开那岛都不存任何幻想
None of those boys had any illusions about ever leaving that island alive
日本军进攻前三天你祖父请求一名空军运输机的枪炮手
so, three days before the Japanese took the island your granddad asked a gunner on an Air Force transport
一个叫维努奇的陌生人
name of Winocki a man he had never met before in his life
把金表带给他还未曾谋面 刚刚出生的幼子
to deliver to his infant son who he had never seen in the flesh his gold watch
三天后 你祖父牺牲了 维努奇很守信
Three days later, your granddad was dead but Winocki kept his word
战后他去拜访你祖母
After the war was over he paid a visit to your gr andmother
给你襁褓中的父亲送去他父亲的金表
delivering to your infant father his dad's gold watch
就是这支表
This watch
你父亲在河内上空被击落时 就带着它
This watch was on your daddy's wrist when he was shot down over Hanoi
他被俘后 关进了越南战俘营
He was captured, put in a Vietnamese prison camp
他知道这支表如果被越南猪发现了会被抢走充公
He knew that if the gooks ever saw the watch they'd confiscate it take it away
在你爸看来 这表就是你的传家宝
The way your dad looked at it, this watch was your birthright
如果被那些猪的脏手碰了他会被诅咒的 于是他藏了起来
He'd be damned if any slopes put their greasy yellow hands on his boy's birthright, so he hid it
有个地方最保险 就是他的屁眼
in one place he knew he could hide somethin'    his ass
五年来他的屁眼一直塞着这玩意
Five long years he wore this watch up his ass
他死于痢疾后 把表交给我
Then he died of dysentery, he give me the watch
我也把这不舒服的金属块儿塞我屁眼两年
I hid this uncomfortable hunk of metal up my ass, two years
被关七年后 我被送回到家人身边
Then    after seven years I was sent home to my family  And
现在…
now
小子 我把表交给你
little man, I give the watch to you
该出场了 布奇
It's time, Butch
(金表)
正式宣布：威尔森死了
It's official  It's official  Wilson is dead!
丹 这是我见过最血腥、最残酷的拳赛！
Dan, that had to be the bloodiest and the most brutal fight this city has ever seen
库利奇已经跑了出去 我从未见过获胜的拳击手这么快地离开拳击场
Coolidge left faster than I've ever seen a victorious boxer leave the ring
你认为他知道威尔森死了吗?
Do you think he knew Wilson was dead?
我猜他知道 理查德 我能看到他眼神中的疯狂
My guess would be yes, Richard  I could see the frenzy in his eyes
我想无论是谁在这种情况下都会像他那样快速地逃出拳击场
give way to the realization of what he was doing  I think any man would have left the ring that fast
你认为这场悲剧会影响世界拳坛吗?
Do you feel this tragedy is gonna have an effect on the world of boxing?
这样的悲剧对拳坛很不利 而且动摇了世界拳坛的基础
Such a tragedy can't help but shake the boxing world to its very foundations
但是在接下来的令人难过的几星期中 最重要的是WBA的眼睛仍然紧紧地盯着…
but par amount importance is during the sad weeks ahead the eyes of the WBA remain
马瑟勒斯
Marsellus?
不关我事…不关我事…
I didn't do it, man
你还好吧?
How you doin'?
很好  忘了感谢你的晚餐呢
Great  I never thanked you for dinner
你查到些什么?      他早有预谋
What you got? He booked
教练呢?
His trainer?
他说不关他事  我相信他
Says he don't know nothin'  I believe him
布奇像耍我们一样耍了他…
Think Butch surprised his ass same as us
我要确切的知道结果    带他去喂狼狗
No, we don't wanna think, we wanna know  Take him to the kennel, sic the dogs on his ass
看他到底知道些什么
We'll find out for goddamn sure what he knows and what he don't
已经派人去抓布奇了 你想怎么处理?
Butch's search    how do you want it done?
搜遍全世界也要找出这杂种
I'm prepared to scour the earth for that motherfucker
就算他逃到印度和中国
If Butch goes to Indo china
我也要找个黑鬼从他米饭里冒出来逮住他
I want a nigger hidin' in a bowl of rice ready to pop a cap in his ass
我会好好处理的
I will take care of it
先生
Mister
先生?   干嘛?
Hey, mister? What?
广播报导的那场拳赛
You were in that fight  The fight on the radio
你是那个拳手
You're the fighter?
你怎么会这么想?
Now, what gave you that idea?
你一定是  我知道你是
You're him  I know you're him
告诉我你就是他
Tell me you're him
我就是他
I'm him
你打死了对手
You killed the other boxing man
他死了?
He's dead?
广播上说的
The radio said he was dead
抱歉  弗洛伊德
Sorry about that, Floyd
那种感觉如何?
What does it feel like?
什么感觉如何?
What does what feel like?
杀人的感觉
Killing a man
赤手空拳打死另一个人
Beating another man to death with your bare hands
你是变态吗?
Are you a weirdo?
不  我只是对这种事很感兴趣
No  It is a subject I have much interest in
你是我见过第一个杀人凶手
You are the first person I've met who has killed somebody
打死人的感觉如何?
So what does it feel like to kill a man?
这样好了
I'll tell you what
给我抽根烟  我就跟你说说
You give me one of them cigarettes you got up there and I'll tell you all about it
艾斯玛瑞达比拉洛佩兹 你是墨西哥人？
So Esmarelda Villalobos  Is that Mexican?
西班牙名字 我是哥伦比亚人
The name is Spanish, but I am Colombian
很不错的名字
That's some handle you got there, honey
谢谢  你叫什么?
Thank you  And what is your name?
布奇
Butch
布奇  什么意思?
Butch  What does it mean?
美国名字没什么狗屁意思
I'm an American, honey  Our names don't mean shit
艾斯玛瑞达  你想知道什么?
So, moving right along, Esmarelda  What is it you wanna know?
我想知道杀人的感觉
I want to know what it feels like to kill a man
我说不出来
I couldn't tell ya
你不告诉我 我都不知道他死了
I didn't know he was dead until you told me he was dead
现在我知道他死了 你想知道我感觉如何?
Now that I know he's dead you wanna know how I feel about it?
我没有感到丝毫难过
I don't feel the least bit bad about it
我他妈是怎么说的？尽快把消息放出去 赌注马上就飙高
What the fuck I tell ya, huh? As soon as the word got out the fix was in, man the odds went through the roof
我知道 真不可思议
I know  I know  Unbelievable
如果他技术好点就不会死
If he was a better boxer, he'd still be alive
如果他把该做的认真做好 把拳套扎紧点也不会死
He never laced up his gloves which he never shoulda done in the first fuckin' place he'd still be alive
谁他妈还管他死活 一切都结束了
who gives a fuck? It's over now
不幸的可怜虫弗洛伊德先生已经说得够多了
Well, enough about the poor unfortunate Mr Floyd
我们说说富有而又成功的布奇先生吧
Let's talk about the rich and prosperous Mr Butch
你向几个组头下了注?
How many bookies you lay it around on?
全部八个?几时收钱?
All eight? How long to collect?
就是说到明天晚上你就都拿到手了?
So you'll have it all by tomorrow night?
我知道有些钱可能收不到
No, I understand, a few stragglers aside
干 斯科特 好消息绝对的好消息 伙计
Oh, fuck, Scotty, that is good news that is great news, man
不 我和法比恩妮一早就走
No, me and Fabienne are gonna leave in the morning
到达诺克斯维尔得花几天时间
It'll probably take us a couple of days to get to Knoxville
好兄弟 你说得没错 该死的一点都没错！
OK, my brother  You're right  You're goddamn right
斯科特我们下次见面得在田纳西州了 淡定点兄弟
All right, Scotty  Next time I see you, we'll be on Tennessee time  Be cool, brother
四十五块六毛
45 60
这里还有点小意思…
And, uh, here's a little    somethin' for the effort
如果有人问你今晚的乘客是谁 你怎么说?
Now if anybody asks you who your fare was tonight what are you gonna say?
说实话啊…
The truth
三个衣冠楚楚 酒醉微醺的墨西哥人
Three well-dressed, slightly toasted Mexicans
晚安 艾斯玛瑞达比拉洛佩兹（西班牙语）
Bonsoir, Esmarelda Villalobos
晚安 布奇（西班牙语）
Buenas noches, Butch
别开灯
Keep the light off
好点吗 小甜心?
Is that better, sugar pop?
嗯
Oui
上班辛苦吗?
Hard day at the office?
很累 我跟人打了一架
Pretty hard  I got in a fight
可怜的宝宝 还有力气亲热吗?
Poor baby  Can we make spoons?
我想先洗个澡 我臭得像只狗
You know what? I was thinkin' about takin' a shower  I'm stinkin' like a dog over here
我喜欢你的味道
Mmm  I like the way you stink
我先脱掉夹克
Let me take this jacket off
刚才我在照镜子      嗯?
I was looking at myself in the mirror
我希望那里变大点
I wish I had a pot
你照镜子 你想哪里想变大点?
You were lookin' at yourself in the mirror and you wish you had some pot?
我的肚皮啦
A pot belly
大肚皮很性感
Pot bellies are sexy
你应该很高兴因为你的肚皮很大
Well, you should be happy cause you have one
闭嘴 胖胖 我的肚皮才不大
Shut up, fatso! I don't have a pot
我只是小腹有点鼓 像麦当娜在《幸运星》里演的那样 那不一样
I have a bit of a tummy like Madonna when she did Lucky Star  It's not the same thing
我看不出有什么区别
I didn't know there was such a difference between a pot belly and a tummy
差别很明显
The difference is huge
如果我有大肚皮你会喜欢吗?
Would you like it if I had a pot belly?
不 男人有大肚皮看上去很蠢就像大猩猩
No  Pot bellies make a man Iook either oafish or like a gorilla
但是在女人身上 大肚皮就很性感
But on a woman, a pot belly is very sexy
全身上下都很正常 脸正常、腿正常、屁股也正常
The rest of you is normal.Normal face, normal legs, normal hips, normal ass
只有肚皮特别大特别圆
but with a big perfectly round pot belly
如果我有大肚皮 我会穿特小号T恤突出它
If I had one, I'd wear a T-shirt two sizes too small to accentuate it
男人会觉得那样很有魅力么?
You think men would find that attractive?
我才不在乎男人的看法
I don't give a damn what men find attractive
很不幸的是 看到的和摸到的可不是一回事
It's unfortunate what we find pleasing to the touch and pleasing to the eye is seldom the same
要是你有大肚皮 我就拿它当沙包
If you had a pot belly I would punch you in it
你要打我的肚皮?
You'd punch me in my belly?
狠狠揍一拳
Right in the belly
我要压着你 用大肚皮压你的胸压你的脸直到你喘不了气
Ah! I'd smother you  I'd drop it right on your face till you couldn't breathe
真的? 真是要闷死我?
You'd do that? Yes  Yes
东西带齐了? 带齐了
Did you get everything? Yes, I did
干的好  小甜心
Good job, sugar pop
一切都顺利吗?
Did everything go as planned?
你没听广播?
You didn't listen to the radio?
我从不听你比赛  你赢了?
I never listen to your fights  Were you the winner?
我赢了
I won, all right
你准备退休吗?
Are you still retiring?
当然
Sure am
一切都成过去了?
So, it all worked out in the finish?
还没完全结束 宝贝儿
We're not at the finish yet, baby
我们很危险 对吗?
We're in a lot of danger, aren't we?
要是他们逮到我们 他们会杀了我们 对吗?
If they find us, they'll kill us, won't they?
但他们抓不到我们 对吧?
But they won't find us, will they?
你还想带我走吗?
Do you still want me to go with you?
我不想成为你的累赘
I don't want to be a burden or a nuisance, it's
说啊
Say it
法比恩妮 我要你陪着我
Fabienne I want you to be with me
永远吗?
Forever?
直到永远
Forever and ever
你爱我吗?
Do you love me?
爱死了
Very, very much
布奇?     什么?
Butch? Yes
能给我口交吗?
Will you give me oral pleasure?
你会给我做吗?
Will you kiss it?
你先来
But you first
好
OK
布奇亲爱的 历险开始了！（法语）
Butch  Mon amour  L'aventure commence
我好像弄断了跟肋骨
I think I cracked a rib
给我口交弄断的?
Giving me oral pleasure?
不 呆瓜 打拳弄断的
No, retard  From the fight
别叫我呆瓜
Don't call me retard
我叫法比…  我叫法比恩妮…
My name is Fabby  My name is Fabienne
住嘴…
Stop it  Stop it
住嘴 笨蛋！我讨厌白痴的声音
Shut up, fuckhead! I hate that mongoloid voice
好的 好的 对不起
Ok,ok,sorry
我收回
I take it back
能给我拿条毛巾吗 美丽的郁金香小姐？
Would you hand me a dry towel, Miss Beautiful Tulip?
嗯 我喜欢你叫我郁金香
Oh, I like that  I like being called a tulip
郁金香比白痴好多了
Tulip is much better than mongoloid
我没叫你白痴
I didn't call you a mongoloid
我叫你呆瓜 我收回了
I called you a retard, and I took it back
布奇
Butch?
干嘛 柠檬派?
Yes, lemon pie
我们要上哪儿?
Where are we going to go?
我不知道 你想去哪就去哪
Well, I'm not sure yet  Wherever you want
这次我们赚了很多钱
We're gonna get a lot of money from this
不过还没有多到让我们永无衣食之忧
but it ain't gonna be the kinda money that we can live like hogs in the fat house forever
我们可以去南太平洋的小岛
I was thinkin' maybe we could go down someplace in the South Pacific
那种地方够我们逍遥好一阵子
The kinda money we're gonna have is gonna carry us a long way down there
如果愿意的话 我们可以去波拉波拉岛
If we wanted, we could live in Bora Bora?
当然行
You betcha
过一阵子 住厌了还可以搬去塔希提或者墨西哥
And if after a while you didn't dig that go someplace else, maybe Tahiti  Mexico
但是我不会西班牙话
But I do not speak Spanish
你也不会讲波拉波拉语啊 而且墨西哥语很简单
Well, you do not speak Bora Boran, either  Besides, Mexican is easy
(西班牙语)
Donde esta el zapateria
什么意思?
What does that mean?
鞋店在哪里?
Where is the shoe store?
先吐掉水
Spit, please
(西班牙语)
Donde esta el zapateria
发音不错
Excellent pronunciation
你真是我的小可人儿
You'll be my little mamacita in no time
(西班牙语)
Que hor a es
现在几点
What time is it?
该睡觉了
Time for bed
睡个好觉 小豆豆
Sweet dreams, jellybean
布奇?
Butch?
算了
Never mind
吓我一跳 你做噩梦了?
Merde  You startled me  Did you have a bad dream?
你在看什么?
What is this you're watching?
动作片 不知道片名
A motorcycle movie  I'm not sure the name
你在看吗?
Are you watchin' it?
算是吧
In a way
现在看暴力片未免太早
It's a little early in the morning for explosions and war
是关于什么的?
What was it about?
我怎么知道? 是你在看的
How should I know, Fabienne? You were the one who was watchin' it
不 笨蛋 你做的梦是关于什么的?
No, imbecile, what was your dream about?
不知道 不记得了
I don't know  I don't remember
我很少记得住梦的内容
It's really rare that I remember my dreams
哦 瞧瞧这个一早起来就脾气暴躁的人
Well, let's look at the grumpy man in the morning
干嘛不起床 我们去买早点
Why don't you get up and we'll get some breakfast?
再亲一个 我就起来
One more kiss, and I'll get up
满意吗?
Satisfied?
满意
Yep
那就起床 懒骨头
Then get up, lazy bones
天啊 现在几点了?
God  Unh  What time is it?
早上九点 我们的火车是几点?
Almost 9:00 in the morning  What time does our train arrive?
十一点
11:00
你知道我早餐想吃什么?
You know what I'm gonna have for breakfast?
什么?柠檬派?
What, lemon pie?
我想吃蓝莓松饼浇枫叶糖浆
I'm gonna order a big plate of blueberry pancakes with maple syrup
再来个糖心蛋外加五根香肠
eggs over easy, and five sausages
你准备喝什么?
Anything to drink with that?
噢 你看起来很帅
Ah, that looks nice
我要喝一大壶柳橙汁 再加上杯黑咖啡
To drink a tall glass of orange juice and a black cup of coffee
然后我还要吃块派
After that, I'm going to have a slice of pie
早上就吃派?
Pie for breakfast?
派什么时候吃都行
Any time of the day is a good time for pie
一样是蓝莓口味
Blueberry pie to go with the pancakes
上面铺满芝士
And on top, a thin slice of melted cheese
我的表呢?
Where's my watch?
在里头呀
It's there
不 没有
No, it's not
你找过了吗?
Have you looked?
当然找过了 不然你以为我他妈在干嘛?
Yes, I fucking looked  What the fuck do you think I'm doing?
你确定拿了?
You sure you got it?
确定 在抽屉旁
Yes  Bedside table drawer
挂在小袋鼠上
On the little kangaroo?
没错 挂在小袋鼠上的
Yes  It was on the little kangaroo
可是这儿没有！
Yeah, well, it's not here now
应该在呀
Well, it should be
应该在 但是却没有 到底他妈的在哪?
It most definitely should be, but it's not here now  So where the fuck is it?
法比恩妮 那是我父亲的表！
Fabienne that was my father's fucking watch
知道他经历了什么样的苦难才把表留给了我吗？
Do you have any idea what he had to go through to get me that watch?
我没时间多说 不过确实是千辛万苦！
I don't have time to go into it, but he went through a lot
别的狗屎东西一把火烧了都没问题
All this other shit you could set on fire
但是我特别交待你不要忘了这支该死的表！
but I specifically reminded you not to forget the fucking watch!
现在仔细想想 你有没有拿?
Now think  Did you get it?
我觉得有拿
I believe so
觉得有?这是什么屁话?有还是没有？
You believe so? What the fuck does that mean? You either did, or you didn't get it!
那我有拿
Then I did
你确定？
Are you sure?
不
No
妈的! 去你妈的!狗杂种！
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! Motherfucker!
你知道你他妈有多蠢吗?
Do you know how fucking stupid you fucking are?
不!
No!
不是你的错
It's not your fault
如果你把它落在公寓里了……
If you left it at the apartment
如果你把它落在公寓里了 不是你的错
If you left it at the apartment, it's not your fault
我叫你带一大堆东西
I had you bring a bunch of stuff
我提醒过你
I reminded you about it,
但是没强调它对我的重要意义
but I didn't illustrate how personal the watch was to me
要是我真在乎那块表 我应该早些告诉你的
If all I gave a fuck about was the watch I should've told you that
你又不是我肚里蛔虫 你怎么会知道
You're not a mind reader, are you?
对不起
L    I'm sorry
不用道歉 我只是不能和你一起吃早点了
Don't be  It just means I can't have breakfast with you
为什么?
Why does it mean that?
因为我得回公寓去拿我的表
Because I got to go back to my apartment and get my watch
那帮歹徒不会正在那找你吧?
Won't the gangsters be looking for you there?
去了就知道了
Well that's what I'm going to find out
要是应付不了 我会想办法溜掉
If they are and I don't think I can handle it Then I'll split
我看见过你的表 我以为我有带 对不起
I saw your watch  I thought I brought it  I'm so sorry
这有些钱 出去给你买松饼吃 早餐愉快！我开你的本田去
Here's some money  Go out and get those pancakes  Have a nice breakfast  I'll take your Honda
在你说蓝莓派之前我就会回来
I'll be back before you can say blueberry pie
蓝莓派
Blueberry pie
当然没这么快 不过不会很久
Maybe not that fast but pretty fast, OK?
好吧
OK
妈的! 有这么多事情可以忘 她妈的竟然忘了我老爸的手表！
Shit! Of all the fucking things she could fucking forget she forgets my father's watch!
我特别提醒她 在桌旁 小袋鼠上
I specifically reminded her  Bedside table, on the kangaroo
我对她说别忘了我老爸的表
I said the words, Don't forget my father's watch
情况不错 布奇
Lookin' good, Butch
《女金刚智破钻石案》
《Modesty Blaise》
这就是你的还击布奇 他们总是低估你
That's how you're going to beat 'em, Butch  They keep underestimating you
数数墙上的小花朵 它们从来不打扰我
Countin' flowers on the wall  That don't bother me at all
玩纸牌到天亮 一直只打51张
Playin' Solitaire till dawn With a deck of 51
抽着烟看袋鼠船长 别告诉我…
Smoking cigarettes And watching Captain Kangaroo Now, don't tell me
混帐东西!
Motherfucker
他死了吗?
He's dead
他死了
我可以替你作证 那人疯了
If you need someone to go to court, I'll be glad to help  That guy was a drunken maniac
他撞了你然后又撞到那辆车
He hit you, and then he crashed into that car
谁?
Who?
他
Him
他奶奶的
I'll be damned
我能帮你做点什么吗?
Can I help you with something?
给我闭上嘴
Shut the fuck up
你给我停下 你在搞什么鬼?
Now, you just wait a goddamn minute now  What the fuck are you up to?
来这儿 狗杂种
Come here, motherfucker!
轮到你难堪了 大男孩 那是自尊在搞鬼
You feel that sting, big boy, huh? That's pride fucking with you, see?
你得克服这鬼东西
You got to fight through that shit
你最好杀了我
You better kill me
是的 有人会被杀掉 有人会把这狗杂种的头轰……
Yeah, somebody's going to get killed  Somebody's going to get their motherfucking head blown to
你他妈的给我住手！
Hold it right there, God damn it
这不关你的事 先生
This ain't none of your business, mister
我偏要管 把枪丢掉
I'm making it my business  Toss the weapon
你不明白 伙计
You don't understand, man
把枪丢掉！
Toss the weapon
把脚从黑鬼身上拿开 手放头后面 到柜台这来
Take your foot off the nigger  Put your hands behind your head  Approach the counter right now
这这杂种想…杀我
This motherfucker's trying to kill me
给我闭嘴 就这样 过来
Shut up  Keep a-comin'  Come on
齐德?       我是梅纳德 蜘蛛抓了一对苍蝇
Zed? It's Maynard. The spider just caught a coupl'a flies.
没人能在我店里杀人除了我和齐德
Nobody kills anybody in my place of business except me or Zed
齐德来了
That's Zed
你不是说等我吗?
I thought you said you waited for me
是啊
I did
那他们怎么会遍体鳞伤?
So how come they're all beat up?
那是他们俩自己打的 他们是打着进来的
They did that to each other, man  They came in fighting
这家伙想枪杀那个
Now, this one right here, he was going to shoot that one
是吗? 你想干掉他 孩子?
Is that right? You going to shoot him, boy?
喂 “格蕾丝”放在外面没问题吧?
Hey, is Grace all right out front?
嗯 今天不是礼拜二吧?
Yeah  It ain't Tuesday, is it?
嗯 今天礼拜四
No  It's Thursday
那就没问题
She ought to be fine
把“怪面”牵出来
Bring out The Gimp
我觉得“怪面”在睡觉
I think The Gimp's sleeping
我猜你现在会去叫醒他的 是吗?
I guess you'll just have to go wake him up, now, won't you?
起来!
Get up
跪下
Get down
你想哪个先来?
Which one of 'em you want to do first?
我还没决定
I ain't for sure yet
抓住一只黑人的脚趾头…
Catch a nigger by the toe
如果他大喊着让他走…
If he hollers let him go
老妈叫我仔细挑 那个人 就是你
My mother said  To pick the perfect one and you are
就是你了 胖子
I guess that means you, big boy
在这里干吗?
You want to do it in here?
不 到后面拉塞尔的老屋子里干吧
No  Let's do it back there in Russell's old room
听起来不错
Sounds good to me
看好这家伙
You keep an eye on this one
给我闭嘴!
Shut the fuck up!
你想拿枪 是吗 齐德?
You want that gun, don't you, Zed?
尽管拿呀
Go ahead and pick it up
继续 拿啊 加油 好小子
Go ahead, pick it up  Come on  Atta boy
我要你把枪拿起来 齐德
I want you to pick it up Zed
站开点 布奇
Step aside, Butch
妈的!
Fuck!
你还好吧?
You OK?
我不好 我他妈离好非常的远
No, man  I'm pretty fucking far from OK
现在怎么办?
What now?
怎么办? 我告诉你吧
What now? Let me tell you what now
我会叫来几个擅长爆菊的黑鬼
I'm going to call a couple of hard pipe-hitting niggers to
他们会带老虎钳和焊枪来这房间整天修理他
go to work on the homes here with a pair of pliers and a blow torch
听见了吗 乡巴佬?
You hear me talking, hillbilly boy?
我不会让你离开我的视线 我要把你的屁股操到中世纪去！
I ain't through with you by a damn sight  I'm going to get medieval on your ass
我是说 现在你和我之间怎么办
I meant, what now between me and you?
噢 是那个“怎么办”
Oh, that what now
我告诉你 我们之间怎么办
I tell you what now between me and you
我和你不怎么办
There is no me and you not no more
那我们扯平了?
So are we cool?
是的 扯平了 不过记得两件事
Yeah, we cool  Two things
别跟人提起这事
Don't tell nobody about this
这件事是你、我
This shit is between me, you
和还有这位即将被碎尸万段的强奸先生之间的事
and Mr  Soon To Be Living The Rest Of His Short-Ass Life In Agonizing Pain rapist here
和其他人无关
It ain't nobody else's business
第二 今天晚上就离开这座城市
Two You leave town tonight right now
走了就别回来 消失掉
And when you're gone you stay gone or you be gone
你已失去在洛杉矶的所有特权 同意吗?
You lost all your L A  Privileges  Deal?
同意
Deal
快走吧
Get your ass out of here
法比…
Fabienne!
法比恩妮 宝贝 快点 我们快走
Fabienne  Come on, baby, come on  Get your shit  We got to go right now
我担心死了 行李怎么办?
I was so worried  What about our bags?
别管行李了 再不走就赶不上火车了
Fuck the bags  If we don't split right now we'll miss the train
我先下楼了
I'll be downstairs
一切顺利吗?
Is everything well?
快点 别问这么多
Just come on! No talking now
我们有危险吗?
Are we in danger?
快点 甜心
Come on, honey!
摩托车从哪儿来的?
Where did you get this motorcycle?
这不是摩托车 这是哈雷
It's not a motorcycle, baby  It's a chopper
那我的本田呢?
What happened to my Honda?
抱歉 撞坏了 拜托你快点
I'm sorry, baby  I had to crash that Honda  Will you come on now, please?
走吧 我们快走
Come on, let's go, let's go
你受了伤?
You're hurt?
只是撞歪鼻梁而己 没什么大不了的 快上来
No, no  I might've broken my nose  It's no biggie  Come on, hop on
宝贝 求你了甜心 你他妈的快点上来好吗?
Baby, please  Honey, we got to hit the fucking road  Get on
过来 对不起 对不起
I'm sorry  Come here, come here  I'm sorry  I'm so sorry
你去这么久 我担心死了！
You were gone so long I started to think dreadful thoughts
对不起 甜心 我不想让你担心
Oh, I'm sorry, sweetie  I didn't mean to worry you
早点好吃吗?      好吃
How was your breakfast? It was good
你有吃蓝莓松饼吗?
Did you get the blueberry pancakes?
没有蓝莓口味 我只好吃了奶酪 你确定没事?
They didn't have blueberry pancakes  I had to get buttermilk  Are you sure you're OK?
宝贝 从早上离开你之后
Honey, since I left you,
无疑经历了一生中最不可思议的一天
this has been without a doubt the single weirdest fucking day of my life
快上来我告诉你
Come on, hop on  I'll tell you all about it
该走了…快点
Come on, get on  Gotta go
这是谁的摩托车?
Whose motorcycle is this?
这是台哈雷 宝贝儿
It's a chopper, baby
这是谁的哈雷?
Whose chopper is this?
齐德的      齐德是谁?
Zed's  Whose chopper is this?
齐德完了  他死定了
Zed's dead, baby Zed's dead
(邦妮的状况)
你有 布莱特 你想操他
Yes, you did, Brett! You tried to fuck him
除了她老婆马瑟勒斯·华莱士不喜欢被任何人操！
And Marsellus Wallace don't like to be fucked By anybody except Mrs  Wallace
噢 上帝啊 我不想死
Oh, God, please  I don't want to die
你读过圣经吗? 读过
You read the Bible, Brett?  Yes!
有段经文现在读应该很合适
Well, there's this passage I got memorized  It sort of fits the occasion
《以西结书》二十五章十七节
Ezekiel 25: 17
正直之人的道路
The path of the righteous man
被小人的自私贪婪和恶人的暴虐专政所笼罩
is beset on all sides by the inequities of the selfish and the tyranny of evil men
以仁慈善良之名引领弱小穿越黑暗之谷的“牧羊人”
Blessed is he who in the name of charity and good will
必将得到神的护佑
shepherds the weak through the Valley of Darkness
因为他守护兄弟同胞、拯救迷途羔羊
for he is truly his brother's keeper and the finder of lost children
我将对那些毒害和屠杀我同胞的人
And I will strike down upon thee with great vengeance and furious anger
充满巨大的仇恨和爆裂的怒火！
those who attempt to poison and destroy My brothers
当我复仇之焰吞噬你的那刻 你会知道我的名字 叫做上帝！
And you will know My name is the Lord when I lay My vengeance upon thee
妈的！  妈的！
I'm fucked  I'm fucked
这是你朋友吗?
Is he a friend of yours?
噢 文森特 这是马文 马文 这是文森特
Oh, Vincent, Marvin  Marvin, Vincent
最好叫他闭嘴 他让我很紧张
Better tell him to shut the fuck up  He's getting on my nerves
马文 马文！我要是你就把那该死的嘴闭上
Marvin  Marvin! I'd knock that shit off if I was you
去死吧！狗娘养的 死吧！
Die, you motherfuckers! Die!
你怎么没告诉我们厕所里头有人?
Why the fuck didn't you tell us somebody was in the bathroom?
你忘了有人在里面还拿着把大枪吗?
You forget someone was in there with a goddamn hand-cannon?
你看这枪的尺寸了吗 那把枪比他人还大
You see the size of that gun he fired at us? It was bigger than him
我们早该被射死了 伙计
We should be fucking dead, man
我知道 我们很走运
I know  We was lucky
不不不 我们不是走运
No, no, no, no  That shit wasn't luck
是吗 也许吧
Yeah, maybe
这是神的干预   知道“神的干预”是什么吗?
This was divine intervention  You know what divine intervention is?
知道
I think so
就是神从天上下来 替我们挡住了子弹
That means that God came down from Heaven and stopped the bullets
完全正确 就是这意思
That's right  That's exactly what it means
神从天上下来替我们挡住了该死的子弹
God came down from Heaven and stopped these motherfucking bullets
我想我们该走了 朱尔斯
I think it's time for us to leave, Jules
别不把它当回事
Don't do that  Don't fucking blow this shit off
刚刚在这里发生的是他妈个神迹！
What just happened here was a fucking miracle
算了吧 朱尔斯 只是凑巧罢了
Chill, Jules  This shit happens
错了 你错了！这事绝非偶然
Wrong  Wrong  This shit doesn't just happen
你想在车上 继续研究神学…
Do you want to continue this theological discussion
还是和条子 在监狱里?
in a car or in a jailhouse with the cops?
我们应该被打死的伙计
We should be fucking dead, my friend
我他妈要你承认刚刚发生的事是个神迹
What happened here was a miracle and I want you to fucking acknowledge it
好吧 这是个神迹 可以走了吗?
All right, it was a miracle  Can we go now?
走吧 小子 快点
Let's go, nigger  Come on
你看过《警察》那片子吗?
You ever seen that show Cops?
我看过一集 是有个警察
I was watching it one time, and there was this cop on
说他在过道里和歹徒进行的一场枪战
and he was talking about this gunfight he had in a hallway with this guy, right?
他对着这家伙打空了子弹 却什么都没打到
And he just unloaded on this guy and nothing happened  He didn't hit nothing
好吧？而他们仅仅是在一条走廊里
OK? It was just him and this guy
我的意思是 虽然很诡异 但就是发生了
I mean, you know it's freaky, but it happens
如果你想当盲人 就跟着牧羊人走 但是我他妈算是想清楚了
You want to play blind man, go walk with the shepherd but me, my eyes are wide fucking open
你他妈说的是什么意思?
What the fuck does that mean?
我的意思就是 从现在起 我要退休了
It means that's it for me  From here on in, you can consider my ass retired
我的老天爷      别亵渎神明
Jesus Christ  Don't blaspheme
去他妈的神!     我让你别说了！
God damn it  I said don't do that
你他妈的让我很抓狂
Why are you fucking freaking out on us?
我马上告诉马瑟勒斯我不干了
Look, I'm telling Marsellus today  I'm through
你为什么不同时告诉他理由?
Why don't you tell him at the same time why?
别担心 我会的
Don't worry  I will
我赌一万块他会笑破肚皮
Yeah, and I'll bet you $ 10,000 he laughs his ass off
我才不在乎
I don't give a damn if he does
马文 你怎么认为?
Marvin, what do you make of all this?
我没什么看法
Man, I don't even have an opinion
你肯定有想法的 你认为是神下凡挡住…
You got to have an opinion  Do you think that God came down from Heaven and stopped
你在搞什么鬼? 他妈的!
What the fuck's happening? Oh, shit, man!
天啊 我把马文的脸 轰掉了
Oh, man, I shot Marvin in the face
你他妈的在干嘛?
Why the fuck did you do that?
我不是故意的 纯粹是意外
Well, I didn't mean to do it  It was an accident
什么他妈的屁事我都见过   可是这…
Oh, man, I've seen some crazy-ass shit in my time
冷静点伙计 我说了这是意外
Chill out, man  I told you it was an accident
很可能 你很可能碾到什么东西了
You probably You went over a bump or something
嘿 这车子根本没有撞到什么东西
Hey, the car didn't hit no motherfucking bump
嘿 伙计 我不是故意射这个杂种的 枪突然走火了
Hey, look, man, I didn't mean to shoot the son of a bitch  The gun went off  I don't know why
很好 瞧你搞得一团糟! 这可是大白天 在城里
Well, look at this fucking mess, man! We're on a city street in broad daylight
我不敢相信      现在就得信 混蛋
I can't believe it, man  Well, believe it now, motherfucker
我们要让这车远离公路
We got to get this car off the road
开着满是血的车会引起警察注意的
You know, cops tend to notice shit like you're driving a car drenched in fucking blood
找个朋友的地方避避不就行了
Just take it to a friendly place, that's all
这里是山谷地带文森特 马瑟勒斯才不会和山谷里的人有交情
This is the Valley, Vincent  Marsellus ain't got no friendly places
朱尔斯 这里他妈也不是我的地盘 伙计
Jules, this ain't my fucking town, man!
妈的!
Shit!
你在干嘛  打电话给我托卢卡湖的朋友
What you doing? I'm calling my partner in Toluca Lake
托卢卡湖在哪？
Where's Toluca Lake?
翻过这座山 布班制片厂旁边
It's just over the hill here, over by Burbank Studios
要是吉米不在家 我真他妈不知到该去哪儿
If Jimmie's ass ain't home I don't know what the fuck we going to do,
在818我没有其他朋友了
man cause I ain't got no other partners in 818
吉米! 在忙什么?我是朱尔斯
Jimmie, yo, how you doing, man? It's Jules  Just listen up, man
听我说 我和搭档遇到点儿麻烦
Me and my homeboy are in some serious fucking shit, man
我们在车里 必须离开公路 马上!
We're in a car, and we got to get off the road pronto
我得借你的车库用几小时
I need to use your garage for a couple hours
我们实在应该体谅吉米的处境
We got to be real fucking delicate with this Jimmie situation
他一句话就可以把我们赶出去
He's one remark away from kicking our asses out the door
如果他那么做了我们该怎么办?
If he does, what do we do?
打电话找到救兵前我们不能走 不过我觉得这事不会到那地步
We ain't leaving till we made a couple calls but I don't want it to reach that pitch
吉米是我的朋友 所以你别他家里指手画脚的
Jimmie's a friend  You don't come into your friend's house and start telling him what's what
叫他别太过分就好了
Just tell him not to be abusive, that's all
他看到马文时差点要抓狂
He kind of freaked out back there when he saw Marvin
站在他的角度想想 早上8点 才刚睡醒 对这事丝毫无心理准备
Well, put yourself in his position  It's 8:00 in the morning  He just woke up  He wasn't expecting this shit
别忘了是谁惹的祸 又是谁是在帮忙
Shit, we got to remember here who's doing who a favor
若这意味着我必须讨好他的话 不帮也罢
If that favor means that I got to take shit then he can stick that favor straight up his ass
妈的！你对这毛巾做了什么?
Nigger, what the fuck did you just do to his towel?
我只有擦手而已
I was drying my hands
你得先洗了手再擦
You're supposed to wash them first
你看到我洗了的啊
You watched me wash them
我只看到你湿了湿手
I watched you get them wet
我洗了 这玩意很难洗干净
I was washing them  This shit's hard to get off
如果他有熔岩皂 我可能会洗得干净点
Maybe if he had Lava, I could've done a better job
我他妈跟你用的同一块肥皂 我怎么没把毛巾弄得像卫生巾一样?
I used the same fucking soap you did and the towel didn't look like no goddamn maxipad
要是被他进来看见成了这模样怎么办?
What if he was to come in here and see his towel like this?
搞得这么糟糕会惹来大麻烦 老兄！
It's shit like this that'll bring this situation to a head, man
我没逼你 好吗?你知道我一直很尊重你
I ain't threatening you with nothing, all right? You know I respect you and all
可是别让我难做人 好吗?
but just don't put me in this position, all right?
好的好的 你这样好好地说就没事
All right  Fine  Fine  Ask me nice like that, no problem
把你的朋友搞定就好 我无所谓
Just go handle your friend  Go ahead  I don't care
该死的 吉米 这咖啡真是人间美味
Mmm  Goddamn, Jimmie  This is some serious gourmet shit
我们以为有速溶咖啡就很好了
Me and Vincent would've been satisfied with some freeze-dried Taster's Choice, right?
嘿 他居然为我们准备这么棒的 这是什么口味的?
Heh! And he springs this serious gourmet shit on us.What flavor is this?
少来这套 朱尔斯
Knock it off, Julie
怎么了?
What?
我不需要你告诉我我的咖啡有多好
I don't need you to tell me how fucking good my coffee is
我自己买的我自己知道
I'm the one who buys it  I know how good it is
要是邦妮去买 只会买一堆垃圾货
When Bonnie goes shopping, she buys shit
我买讲究昂贵的咖啡 因为我不仅是喝 还要品尝
I buy the gourmet expensive stuff because when I drink it, I want to taste it
但你知道现在我关心的是什么吗？不是我厨房里的咖啡
But you know what's on my mind right now? It ain't the coffee in my kitchen
而是我车库里的死黑鬼
It's the dead nigger in my garage
噢 吉米 别担心
Oh, Jimmie, don't even worry about it
我什么都不关心 我只想问你一个问题
I don't think about anything  I want to ask you a question
你开车来的时候看到我家门口写着“黑鬼停尸房”的指示牌了吗?
When you came pulling in here did you notice a sign out in the front of my house that said Dead Nigger Storage?
吉米 你知道我没有…
Jimmie, you know I didn't see no shit
你看到我家门口写着“黑鬼停尸房”的指示牌了吗?
Did you notice a sign in the front of my house that said Dead Nigger Storage?
没 我没有
No  I didn't
你知道为什么没看到吗? 为什么?
You know why you didn't see that sign? Why?
因为根本没写 因为给黑人收尸不关我鸟事
Cause it ain't there cause storing dead niggers ain't my fucking business!
吉米 我们不想把那狗杂种放…
Jimmie, we're not going to store the motherfucker
难道你们不了解吗老兄?要是邦妮回到家
Don't you fucking realize, man, that if Bonnie comes home
看到房子里的尸体 就会跟我离婚
and finds a body in her house, I'm going to get divorced?
不用离婚顾问 不必试验分居 就能直接离婚 懂吗?
No marriage counselor, no trial separation  I'm going to get fucking divorced, OK?
我他妈的不想离婚!
And I don't want to get fucking divorced
老兄 你知道的 我想帮你 但我不想失去我老婆 明白吗？
Now, man, you know, fuck, I want to help you but I don't want to lose my wife doing it, all right?
吉米 她不会离开你的
Jimmie, she ain't going to leave you
别他妈叫我吉米 朱尔斯 懂吗？别他妈叫得这么亲密
Don't fucking Jimmie me, Jules! OK? Don't fucking Jimmie me
不管你说什么 我都不会忘记我爱着我的妻子
There's nothing you're gonna say that's gonna make me forget that I love my wife, is there?
现在 离他下班回家还有一个半小时
Look, you know she comes home from work in about an hour and a half
她在医院上夜班 你需要打电话吗?
Graveyard shift at the hospital  You got to make some phone calls?
你能通知什么人吗?赶快去做 在她回家之前把那尸体弄走
You got to call some people? Well, then do it, and get the fuck out of my house before she gets here
我们人手很多 没问题 我们不会害你的
That's Kool and the Gang  We don't want to fuck your shit up
我只想叫我的人来 替我们解围
I want to call my people, get them to bring us in
你已经他妈的把我害惨了！
You're fucking my shit up right now!
要是邦妮回来了 你们还会把我害得更惨！
You'll fuck my shit up big time if Bonnie comes home
所以 请帮个忙好吗?电话在卧室里 我建议你快点去
So just do me that favor, all right? The phone is in my bedroom  I suggest you get going
好吧 说说要是她回到家里 她会怎么做?
Well, say she comes home  What do you think she'll do?
噢 这不是废话吗!她会抓狂的 毫无疑问
Oh, no fucking shit, she'll freak  That ain't no kind of answer
我是说 她会有点抓狂 还是很抓狂?
I mean, you know, I don't  How much? A lot or a little?
你得了现在邦妮的状况是多么紧急
You got to appreciate what an explosive element this Bonnie situation is
她忙了整晚回到家里
I mean, if she comes home from a hard day's work
发现一伙歹徒在厨房里为非作歹…
and finds a bunch of gangsters in her kitchen doing a bunch of gangster shit
她会有什么反应还用说吗？
there ain't no telling what she's liable to do
嗯 我了解 朱尔斯 我只是在设想各种可能性
Yeah, I've grasped that, Jules  All I'm doing is contemplating the ifs
我不想听什么狗屁可能性
I don't want to hear about no motherfucking ifs
你要听到的是你说：你不会有麻烦的朱尔斯 我会搞定
All I want to hear from your ass is You ain't got no problem Jules  I'm on the motherfucker
回去把那黑鬼弄出来 然后等救兵来 很快就到
Go back in there, chill them niggers out and wait for the cavalry, which will be coming directly
你不会有麻烦的朱尔斯 我会搞定
You ain't got no problem, Jules  I'm on the motherfucker
回去把那黑鬼弄出来 然后等“头狼”来 很快就到
Go back in there and chill them niggers out and wait for The Wolf, who should be coming directly
你会派“头狼”来?
You're sending The Wolf?
怎么 感觉好些了 混蛋
Oh, you feel better, motherfucker?
黑鬼 你早该这么说！
Shit, negro, that's all you had to say
她是那种歇斯底里的人吗? 她几点回家?
Is she the hysterical type? When is she due?
再念一次人员名单
Give me the principals' names again
朱尔斯（黑人） 嗯
Jules  Mm-hmm
文森特（白人）
Vincent
吉米  邦妮  好的
Jimmie  Bonnie  Mm-hmm
(一具无头尸体)
三十分钟车程   我十分钟就到
It's thirty minutes away  I'll be there in ten
(九分三十七秒后)
你是吉米吗? 这是你家?
You're Jimmie, right? This is your house?
当然
Sure is
我是温斯顿·沃夫 来解决问题
I'm Winston Wolf  I solve problems
太好了 我们刚好碰到麻烦
Good  We got one
我听说了 我能进来吗?
So I heard  May I come in?
请进
Yeah, please do
你一定是朱斯 所以你是文森特
You must be Jules which would make you Vincent
让我们进入正题吧先生们
Let's get down to brass tacks, gentlemen
如果我得到的信息无误 时间非常紧 对吗吉米?
If I was informed correctly the clock is ticking, is that right, Jimmie?
非常正确
100%
尊夫人邦妮九点半到家对吗?
Your wife Bonnie comes home at 9:30 in the a m , is that correct?
对
Uh-huh
我们有理由相信她回来看到这些 应该不会欣赏吧？
I was led to believe if she comes home and finds us here she wouldn't appreciate it none too much?
她不会欣赏的
She wouldn't at that
我们只有40分钟时间把尸体搬走
That gives us forty minutes to get the fuck out of Dodge
照我说的做 时间充足
which, if you do what I say when I say it, should be plenty
现在 车上有具无头尸体 带我去看看
Now, you got a corpse in a car minus a head in a garage  Take me to it
吉米?
Jimmie?
我想我闻到了咖啡香 能给我倒一杯吗?
I thought I smelled some coffee back there  Would you make me a cup?
没问题
Yeah, sure
你要加什么?
Oh, how do you take it?
多点奶 多点糖
Lots of cream, lots of sugar
这辆车的性能有什么要交代的？
About the car is there anything I need to know?
会抛锚 会冒烟吗? 有杂音吗?汽油足吗?
Does it stall, smoke, make a lot of noise? Is there gas in it? Anything?
看外表就知道这车很不俗
Aside from how it looks, the car is cool
确定吗? 别开出去发现没刹车灯
Positive? Don't get me out there on the road I find out the brake lights don't work
老兄 据我所知 这玩意状况绝佳
Man, far as I know, the motherfucker's tiptop
很好 我们先回厨房
Good enough  Let's go back to the kitchen
你的咖啡 沃夫先生
Here you go, Mr  Wolf
谢谢你 吉米
Thank you, Jimmie
首先 你们两个把尸体塞进行李厢
OK, first thing you two, take the body, stick it in the trunk
吉米 这房子这么干净
Now, Jimmie, this looks to be a pretty domesticated house
让我相信车库或者水槽下面一定有很多清洁剂之类的
That would lead me to believe that in the garage or under the sink, you got a bunch of cleaners and shit?
是的 沃夫先生 在洗脸槽底下
Yeah, Mr  Wolf  Under the sink
很好 我要你们俩做的是拿着这些清洁用品去把车里打扫干净
Good  What I need you two fellas to do is take those cleaning products and clean the inside of the car
动作要快、快、快
I'm talking fast, fast, fast
得把后座上的脑浆和头骨碎片都清理出来
Go in the back seat scoop up all those little pieces of brain and skull
舀出来后 把车内擦干净 不必太仔细
Get it out of there  Wipe down the upholstery  Now, it don't need to be spick-and-span
你们又不需要吃光它们 所以看上去过得去就行了
You don't need to eat off it  Just give it a good once over
真正需要下功夫的是那些一团糟的地方
What you need to take care of are the really messy parts
一滩滩的血迹一定要彻底吸干净
The pools of blood that have collected you got to soak that shit up
吉米 我们到你的储物间去
Now, Jimmie, we need to raid your linen closet
我需要毯子 棉被 床单之类的东西
I need blankets I need comforters I need quilts I need bedspreads
越厚越黑越好 白的不行
The thicker the better, the darker the better No whites  Can't use 'em
我们得掩饰车子内部
We need to camouflage the interior of the car
前座、后座还有地板都铺上被子和毯子
We're going to line the front seat and back seat and the floorboards with quilts and blankets
要是被警察拦下仔细检查的话恐怕会穿帮
So if a cop stops us and sticks his big snout in the car the subterfuge won't last
可是乍看之下这车都很正常
but at a glance, the car will appear to be normal
吉米 你带路 开工了
Jimmie, lead the way  Boys, get to work
说声“请”会更好
Please would be nice
你说什么?
Come again?
我说：说声"请"会更好
I said a please would be nice
我直说吧混球 我来这里不是为了说“请”
Get it straight, buster  I'm not here to say please
我是来这是告诉你们该怎么做
I'm here to tell you what to do
如果你还有自救的本能 你他妈最好快动手去干
And if self-preservation is an instinct you possess you better fucking do it and do it quick
我是来帮忙的 如果你不需要 那祝你好运先生
I'm here to help  If my help is not appreciated, lots of luck, gentlemen
不 沃先生 不是的 很感激你的帮助
No, Mr  Wolf, it ain't like that  Your help is definitely appreciated
我不想失礼好吗？我很尊重你
I don't mean disrespect, OK? I respect you
我只是不想被人当小弟使唤
I don't like people barking orders at me, that's all
如果我对你有所不周 那是因为时间紧迫
If I'm curt with you, it's because time is a factor
我想得快说得快 也希望你们行动快 如果你们还想脱身的话
I think fast, I talk fast and I need you guys to act fast if you want out of this
好吧 我诚心邀请你们去清理那讨厌的车
so pretty please with sugar on top clean the fucking car
别那样看着我好吗？我能感觉到
Don't be looking at me like that, all right? I can feel your look
一九七四年雪佛兰新星  绿色
It's a 1974 Chevy Nova  Green
除了车里一团糟  没别的
Nothing except for the mess inside
二十分钟到 没人会出错的
Mmm, about twenty minutes  Nobody who'll be missed
你真是好人 乔 非常感谢
You're a good man, Joe  Thanks a bunch
进展如何 吉米?
How we coming, Jimmie?
很好 我都找出来了 不过…
Pretty good  I got it all here but, uh
沃夫先生 你得了解…
Mr  Wolf, you got to understand something
叫我温士顿 吉米 请教我温斯顿
Winston, Jimmie, please  Winston
你得了解 温斯顿
You got to understand something now, Winston
不用 谢了
Uh, no, thank you
这些是我最好的被子…
This is our best linen here
是康舅和金姨送的结婚礼物
and it was a wedding present from my Uncle Conrad and my Aunt Ginny
他们都不在了  我很想帮忙
and they're not with us anymore  I really want to help you guys out
我问个问题 你不会介意吧?
Let me ask you a question, Jimmie if you don't mind
不会的 请说
No, please, go ahead
康舅和金姨是百万富翁吗?
Your Uncle Conrad and Aunt Ginny were they millionaires?
不是
No
你马瑟勒斯叔叔是
Well, your Uncle Marsellus is
我很肯定要是康舅和…
and I'm positive if Uncle Conrad and Aunt
金姨
Ginny
还在的话 他们还会送你全套卧室装修
Ginny were here  they would furnish you with a whole bedroom set
马瑟勒斯叔就会很乐意这么做
which your Uncle Marsellus is more than happy to do
我喜欢橡木家具 我卧室就有一套
I like oak myself  That's what I have in my bedroom
你呢吉米? 你喜欢橡木吗?
How about you, Jimmie? You an oak man?
橡木不错
Oak's nice
这事儿我决不原谅你 真他妈的让人恶心
I will never forgive your ass for this shit  This is some fucked-up repugnant shit
朱尔斯 有句成语听过吗?
Jules, did you ever hear the philosophy
知错能改 善莫大焉
that once a man admits that he is wrong that he is immediately forgiven for all wrongdoings?
你小子别跟我扯谈!
Get the fuck out my face with that shit
说这话的人决不会因为你的愚蠢而被迫亲手收拾七零八碎的头骨
The motherfucker said that shit never had to pick up itty-bitty pieces of skull on account of your dumb ass
现在 我要到极限了朱尔斯 我受够这种虐待了
I got a threshold, Jules  I got a threshold for the abuse that I will take
现在我是一辆跑车知道吗？然后你把我变成了红色
Right now, I'm a fucking race car, all right? And you got me in the red
让一辆跑车变成红色是他妈的非常危险的
I'm just saying that it's fucking dangerous to have a race car in the fucking red, that's all
我要爆发了    噢 你要爆发了?
I could blow  Oh, you ready to blow?
没错 我马上要爆炸了
Yeah, I'm ready to blow
那我就他妈就是原子弹 你个杂种
I'm a mushroom cloud-laying motherfucker, motherfucker
再碰到脑浆 我就是TNT炸药 我就是纳瓦隆突击队的机枪
Every time my fingers touch brain, I'm Superfly TNT  I'm The Guns of the Navarone
我他妈的在后座上干什么?
In fact, what the fuck am I doing in the back?
你他妈才该来收拾这脑浆
You the motherfucker who should be on brain detail
他妈的换位置 我洗窗 你清理黑鬼的头骨
We fucking switching  I'm washing the windows and you picking up this nigger's skull
干得不错先生们 应该可以脱身
Fine job, gentlemen  We may get out of this yet
不敢相信是同一部车
I can't believe this is the same car
别急着互相甜菊
Let's not start sucking each other's dicks quite yet
第一阶段已经完成 清洗完汽车 接着第二步清洗你们两个
Phase one is complete    clean the car which moves us right along to phase two clean you two
给我脱
Strip
全部脱光?
All the way?
一丝不挂
To your bare ass
两位快点
Quickly, gentlemen
再过十五分钟吉米的贤妻就回来了
We got about fifteen minutes before Jimmie's better half pulls into the driveway
妈的 早上真他妈冷
Damn  This morning air is some chilly shit
你确定这有必要吗?
Are you sure this is absolutely necessary?
知道你们俩像什么吗？    像什么？
You know what you two look like? What?
两个刚刚轰掉别人脑袋的家伙
Like a couple of guys who just blew off somebody's head
脱掉那些血衣是绝对必要的
Stripping off those bloody rags is absolutely necessary
把它们丢进垃圾袋里
Toss them in Jim's garbage bag
千万别干蠢事 比如把这些放在你家门口等清洁工来收走
Don't do nothing stupid like leaving this shit out front for Otto the Garbageman you know what I'm saying?
别担心我们会一起带走   吉米 肥皂
Don't worry  We're taking it with us  Jim, the soap
文森特
Vincent
先生们 我确信你们一定坐过牢   来了
OK, gentlemen you've both been to County before I'm sure  Here it comes
妈的  冻死我了
Goddamn! The water's fucking cold
比我好受多了 先生们
Better you than me, gentlemen
肥皂要尽量多抹点
Don't be afraid of the soap  Spread it around
上面一点
Get him up there a little bit
我的头发快冲点水 快点 他妈的快点
Vincent's hair  Come on, do it, God damn it! Do it!
毛巾
Towel 'em
干了就把衣服给他们
They're dry enough  Toss them their clothes
太好了  订做的都没这么合身
Perfect  We couldn't have planned this better
你们像… 他们像什么吉米?
You guys look like What do they look like, Jimmie?
呆瓜  他们像一对大呆瓜
Dorks  They look like a couple of dorks
哈哈哈 那可是你的衣服 傻逼
Ha ha ha  They're your clothes, motherfucker
快点  再开玩笑就走不了了 别让我求你们
Come on, gentlemen  We're laughing our way right into prison  Don't make me beg
先生们 路上的规矩听好
OK, gentlemen, let's get our rules of the road straight
我们要去魔鬼乔拖车行
We're going to a place called Monster Joe's Truck and Tow
魔鬼乔和他女儿拉奎尔很同情我们的处境
Now, Monster Joe and his daughter Raquel are sympathetic to our dilemma
那地方在北好莱坞 过几个路口就到 我们得上好莱坞大道
The place is North Hollywood so a few twists and turns aside, we'll be going up Hollywood Way
我来开车  朱斯跟我坐
Now, I'll drive the tainted car  Jules, you ride with me
文森特  你开我的讴歌跟着
Vincent, you follow in my Acura
经过约翰劳斯路时 任何人都不准轻举妄动 除非有我的指示
Now, if we come across the path of any John Q  Laws nobody does a fucking thing till I do something
我刚说什么?
What did I say?
别轻举妄动除非      除非什么?
Don't do shit unles Unless what?
有你的指示
Unless you do it first
你真像个天才
Spoken like a true prodigy
你呢? 你不会给我出状况吧?
How about you, Lash LaRue? Can you keep your spurs from jingling and jangling?
沃夫先生 我的枪走了火 不是故意的 我保证会保持冷静
Mr  Wolf, look, the gun went off  I don't why  I'm cool  I promise you
那就好  我开车很快  要跟紧
Fair enough  Now, I drive real fucking fast, so keep up
要是弄坏我的车 魔鬼乔就会处理两具尸体
If I get my car back any different than I gave it Monster Joe's going to be disposing of two bodies
别挡路 雷克斯
Out of my way, Rex
没事了?
We cool?
好像什么也没发生过
Like it never happened
小伙子们 这是拉奎尔
Boys, this is Raquel
有一天她会接管这里
Someday, all this will be hers
你们准备去打排球吗?
You guys going to a volleyball game or something?
我带小姐出去吃早餐 也许可以稍你们一程 你们住哪?
I'm taking my lady out for breakfast  Maybe I could drop you two off  Where do you live?
雷东诺海岸   英格尔伍德
Redondo  Inglewood
呃 我看到了…你们的未来：去坐出租车
（模仿电影The Dead Zone (1983) （再死一次）中Johnny Smith及其超能力）
It's  it's your future  L   I see a   a cab ride  Move out of the sticks, fellas
说晚安  拉奎尔
Say good night, Raquel
晚安  拉奎尔
Good night, Raquel
后会有期  别惹麻烦  疯小子们
I'll see you guys around  Stay out of trouble, you crazy kids
沃夫先生 你的功力真令人佩服
Mr  Wolf, I just want to tell you it was a real pleasure watching you work
没错  非常感谢你  沃夫先生
Yeah, really, and thank you very much, Mr  Wolf
叫我温士顿
Call me Winston
看见了吗小姐? 尊敬长者才有品格
You see that, young lady? Respect  Respect for one's elders shows character
我很有品格
I have character
你有性格不代表你有品格
Because you are a character doesn't mean that you have character
一起搭车吧?
Want to share a cab?
我饿了 要一起吃早餐吗?
I could go for some breakfast  Feel like having breakfast with me?
好啊
Cool
我以为他是欧洲人
I don't know why, I thought he'd be European
他是“英国鲍勃”那样的欧洲人
（“英国鲍勃”是经典西部片《不可饶恕》里的角色）
Yo, man, he's about as European as English Bob
我知道……不过
I know that now, but
他是不是很酷?
Was he cool or what?
他妈的酷呆了 一切都在掌控之中
Totally fucking cool, in control
甚至你惹他的时候他都没真的生气 我非常惊讶
Didn't even really get pissed when you were fucking with him  I was amazed
来点培根吧
Want some bacon?
我不吃猪肉
No, man  I don't eat pork
你是犹太人吗?
Are you Jewish?
不是  我只是不喜欢猪
Naw, I ain't Jewish  I just don't dig on swine, that's all
为什么?
Why not?
猪是龌龊的动物  我不吃龌龊的动物
Pigs are filthy animals  I don't eat filthy animals
可是培根和猪排都很好吃
Yeah, but bacon tastes good  Pork chops taste good
阴沟里的老鼠可能和南瓜饼一样香 但我永远不会知道
Hey, a sewer rat may taste like pumpkin pie but I'd never know
因为我也不会吃那肮脏的烂东西
cause I wouldn't eat the filthy motherfuckers
猪在大粪里吃喝睡觉 是龌龊的动物
Pigs sleep and root in shit  That's a filthy animal
别想让我吃那些连自己的粪便都不在乎的东西
I ain't eating nothing that ain't got sense enough to disregard its own feces
那狗呢? 狗吃自己的屎
How about a dog? A dog eats his own feces
我也不吃狗肉
I don't eat dog, either
可是你觉得狗龌龊吗?
But do you consider a dog to be a filthy animal?
我还不至于把狗当作污秽的动物 不过狗确实很脏
I wouldn't go so far as to call a dog filthy but they're definitely dirty
但狗具有人性 这就够了
But a dog's got personality  Personality goes a long way
照你这么说 如果猪稍有人性 它就不龌龊了是吗？
Ah, so by that rationale if a pig had a better personality he would cease to be a filthy animal Is that true?
那我们说的一定是一头万人迷猪
We'd have to be talking about one charming motherfucking pig
它必须得比《绿色田野》里的阿诺德还要迷人十倍 懂吗?
（阿诺德是电影《绿色田野》里的粉红小猪）
He'd have to be ten times more charming than Arnold on Green Acres, you know what I'm saying?
噢 老兄 妙极了
Oh, man, that's good
笑死人了  你开始放松心情了
That's good, man  You're starting to lighten up
刚才你绷着脸好沉闷
You been sitting there all serious and shit
我只是在想事情
Man, I've just been sitting here thinking
想什么?
About what?
我们目睹的神迹
About the miracle we witnessed
神迹是你目睹的  我只是看见恐怖的巧合
The miracle you witnessed  I witnessed a freak occurrence
神迹是什么? 文森特?
What is a miracle, Vincent?
神做的事
An act of God
神做的事是什么?
And what's an act of God?
神把不可能的事变成可能
God makes the impossible possible
不过早上的事不能算
But this morning I don't think qualifies
你不明白吗？这都不重要 你思考的方法都是错的
Don't you see? That shit don't matter  You're judging this shit the wrong way
神可以挡住子弹也可以把可口可乐变成百事
I mean, it could be God stopped the bullets or he changed Coke to Pepsi，
他让我开窍了
he found my fucking car keys
不能仅用世俗的眼光去看这事
You don't judge shit like this based on merit
这件事是不是神迹 并不重要
Now, whether or not what we experienced was an According to Hoyle miracle is insignificant
有意义的是我感觉到了神的存在 神的干预
but what is significant is I felt the touch of God  God got involved
但是为什么?
But why?
我就是不知道为什么才操蛋 但是我不能回去睡大觉
Well, that's what's fucking with me  I don't know why, but I can't go back to sleep
你不是真的想放弃吧?
You're really thinking about quitting?
这种生活? 对呀
The life? Yeah
非常肯定
Most definitely
那你打算做什么?
What you going to do, then?
我就是在想这个
Well, that's what I've been sitting here contemplating
首先 我得先把皮箱送回去给马瑟勒斯
First, I'm going to deliver this case to Marsellus
然后 基本上 就是行走江湖
Then, basically, I'm just going to walk the earth
你什么意思 行走江湖?
What you mean,walk the earth?
像凯恩在电影《功夫》里一样
You know, like Caine in Kung Fu
从一个地方到另一个地方 到处交友和历险
Walk from place to place,meet people,get in adventures meet people,get in adventures
你打算云走多久?
And how long do you intend to walk the earth?
直到神指示我停下
Till God puts me where he wants me to be
要是他没指示呢?
And what if he don't do that?
那我就永远走下去
If it takes forever, then I'll walk forever
所以你打算当个乞丐?
So you decided to be a bum?
我打算当我自己文森特 就这么简单
I'll just be Jules, Vincent    no more, no less
不 朱尔斯 你打算当个乞丐！
No, Jules  You decided to be a bum
像外面那些狗屎般一样
Just like all those pieces of shit out there
乞讨零钱 睡在垃圾袋 吃别人扔的东西
who beg for change who sleep in garbage bins, eat what I throw away
他们有个名字朱尔斯 叫做：叫花子
They got a name for that, Jules  It's called a bum
没工作、没住所、没有钱
And without a job, a residence, or legal tender that's what you're going to be
老兄 你将会变成他妈的叫花子
man  You're going to be a fucking bum
朋友 这就是我们看法的不同
Look, my friend, this is just where you and I differ
小弟！咖啡！
Garcon! Coffee!
我承认早上的事的确很罕见
What happened this morning, man, I agree it was peculiar
但并不像水掺在酒里难以分辨
Garcon means boy  But water into wine  I
不管什么样的都能分辨 文森特
All shapes and sizes, Vincent
别他妈这么和我说话老兄！
Don't fucking talk to me that way, man
如果我的答案吓到你了文森特 就不要再问那些让你害怕的问题
If my answers frighten you, Vincent then you should cease asking scary questions
我要去撇大条
I'm going to take a shit
你什么时候决定的?刚才吃松饼的时候？
When did you make this decision? When you were sitting there eating that muffin?
对啊我边喝咖啡 边吃松饼 边回想刚才的一幕
Well, yeah  I was sitting here eating my muffin and drinking my coffee and replaying the incident in my head
就有了酒鬼所谓的"片刻清醒"
when I had what alcoholics refer to as a moment of clarity
操  待会再说
Fuck  To be continued
我爱你  小南瓜
I love you, Pumpkin
我也爱你  小兔兔
And I love you, Honey Bunny
都别动 抢劫了
Everybody be cool! This is a robbery!
谁他妈敢乱动一下 我就把你们这些杂种统统杀光！
Any of you fucking pricks move and I'll execute every one of you motherfuckers!
懂了吗？安静！
You got that? You just be quiet!
趴下 他妈的趴下
Get the fuck down! Get the fuck down!
你在一个盲点 带着你的女人到那边角上的座位去
You, you're in a blind spot  Take your dames to that booth
我只数到十秒
on the count of ten
厨房里墨西哥佬滚出来！
Mexicans out of the fucking kitchen!
1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight!
嘿 你 把那个袋子给我
Hey, you, throw those bags!
贱人 快点 出来 出来
Fucking wanker! Move! Move!
老头儿 蹲下
Grandpa, down!
我是这儿的经理 好商量 有事好商量
I'm the manager here, there's no problem, no problem at all
你想惹麻烦吗?    噢先生 我不想
You're going to give me a problem? No, sir, I'm not
我认为你想给我找麻烦 你想给我找麻烦？
I thought you said you're going to give me a fucking problem! You're going to give me a fucking problem?
这里有人逞英雄 小兔兔
I think we got a hero here, Honey Bunny!
把他毙了
Well, just execute him!
我没逞英雄 我是这的经理
I am not a hero  I'm just a coffee shop
餐馆是我们的啦！
The restaurant's ours!
要拿什么尽管拿
Just take whatever you want
安抚一下客人  好
You talk to the customers  Yeah
叫他们别轻举妄动就没事   懂吗?
You tell them to be fucking cool and everything will be over! You understand me?
懂
Yes
请大家冷静点 照他们说的做合作 很快就会没事了
Listen, everybody  Be calm cooperate and this will all be over in a minute
蹲下来  很好
Get the fuck down! Well done
《女金刚智破钻石案》
《Modesty Blaise》
大家听好了 我会来收钱包
All right, now, people I'm going to come around and collect your wallets
别他妈出声 把钱包丢进袋子里懂吗?
You don't fucking talk  You just throw them in the bag  Are we clear?
你们他妈的懂了吗？
I said, are we fucking clear?
很好  钱包拿出来
Good  Now wallets out
放进袋子   袋子里
That's it  Get the fuck down  In the bag  In the fucking bag!
我啥都没有 老兄
I don't have nothing on me, man
我他妈在等啥? 放袋子里
What am I waiting for? In the fucking bag
小费放进来
Laura? Laura, tips  In the bag   Yeah
大哥大? 丢进来
Is that a cellular phone? Yeah  In the fucking bag
很好  趴下来  放进来…
Tidy up, tidy up  That's it  Now get the fuck down on the floor
放进来
In the bag
皮箱里是什么?
What's in the case?
老板的脏衣服
My boss's dirty laundry
你老板叫你洗衣服?
Your boss makes you do his laundry?
没错
When he wants it clean
烂差事
Sounds like a shit job
我正好也这么想
Funny  I was thinking the same thing
打开
Open it
恐怕不行
Afraid I can't do that
我没听见
I didn't hear you
你听见了
Yes, you did
怎么回事?
What's going on?
这里好像有个咸蛋超人
Looks like we got a vigilante in our midst
把他的脑袋轰掉
Shoot him in the face
不是吓唬你 我可不是第一次被枪指着了
I hate to shatter your ego, but this ain't the first time I've had a gun pointed at me
不交出皮箱  你就甭想活命
You don't take your hand off that case, it'll be your last
别惹麻烦 你会害我们都被杀掉的
Stop causing problems! You'll get us all killed!
给他们想要的他们就会离开的
Give 'em what you got and get 'em out of there!
你他妈的住嘴  肥猪  这不关你的事
Shut the fuck up, fat man! This ain't none of your goddamn business
别激动  小兔兔  没事
Be cool, Honey Bunny  Be cool
没问题 局面已经控制好了
No problerm,I got it under control.
我数到三
Now I'm going to count to three
不打开皮箱  我就轰掉你脑袋
If you don't open that case I'm going to unload in your fucking face
懂了吗?
We clear?
一
one
二
two
三  好了林戈 你赢了
（林戈：Ringo 是59年西部片《Johnny Ringo》中的著名大盗）
three  OK, Ringo  You win
他是你的了
It's yours
打开它
Open it
什么? 是什么?
What is it? What is it?
我没看错吧?
Is that what I think it is?
没有
Mm-hmm
太美了
It's beautiful
到底是什么玩意?
God damn it, what is it?
放开他! 放开他!
You let him go! You let him go! Let go of him!
叫那母狗冷静点  说冷静点
Tell that bitch to be cool! I'm gonna kill you! Say, Bitch, be cool! Be cool, Honey Bunny!
冷静点  甜心      冷静点
Say, Bitch, be cool! Be cool!
叫她别乱叫
Tell that fuckin' bitch to chill!
冷静点  甜心
Be cool, Honey Bunny!
叫那婊子放松点！
Chill that fuckin' bitch out!
放松点  甜心
Chill out, Honey Bunny!
- Let go of him! - JULES: Chill!
跟她说不会有事的
Promise her!
不会有事的      向她保证
I promise!
我保证      叫她镇定
Tell her to chill!
镇定点  小兔兔
Just chill out, Honey Bunny!
她叫什么名字?   尤兰达
Now tell me her name  Yolanda
尤兰达  我们什么蠢事都不会做的对吗？
All right, now, Yolanda!  We're not gonna do anything stupid, are we?
别伤害他
Don't you hurt him!
不会的  我们要学方斯  方斯是什么样的?
（方斯是美国著名情景喜剧Happy Day的重要角色）
Nobody's gonna hurt anybody  We're all gonna be like three little Fonzies here  And what's Fonzie like?
尤兰达  方斯是怎样的?
Come on, Yolanda, what's Fonzie like?!
他很酷      什么?
He's cool? What?
他很酷      答对了
Cool  Correctamundo!
我们要学他很冷静
And that's what we're gonna be  We're gonna be cool
现在林戈 等我数到三
Now, Ringo, I'm gonna count to three  And when I count three
我想让你扔掉枪 把手放在桌上然后坐下
I want you to let go of your gun put your palms flat on the table and sit your ass down
不要轻举妄动 冷静点 好了吗?
But when you do it, you do it cool  You ready?
一、二、三
One  two  three
现在放他走
OK, now you let him go!
冷静点 你对我大喊大叫 我会紧张
Yolanda, I thought you were gonna be cool  Now, when you yell at me, it makes me nervous
我一紧张就会害怕
And when I get nervous,I get scared
一害怕他妈的枪就容易走火
And when motherfuckers get scared that's when motherfuckers accidentally get shot
你要知道 伤害他 你就死定了
Just know, you hurt him, you die  Well,
看来情况就是这样
that seems to be the situation.
但是我不想这样
But I don't want that,
你也不想这样
and you don't want that
这位林戈也肯定不想这样
and Ringo here definitely doesn't want that
所以让我们看看能做些什么
So let's see what we can do
情况是这样的
Now,here's the situation
通常你们两个会像炸鸡一样被我宰掉
Normally both your asses would be dead as fuckin' fried chicken
不过恰好我正想改过自新
but you happened to pull this shit while I'm in a transitional period
我不想杀你  我想帮你
and I don't want to kill you  I want to help you
但这皮箱不能给你 它不是我的
But I can't give you this case, 'cause it don't belong to me
况且为这皮箱  你们这些蠢蛋让我受了太多罪
Besides, I been through too much shit over this case to just hand it over to your dumb ass
文森特  冷静点
Vincent! Be cool!
尤兰达 没事的  宝贝  没事
Yolanda, it's cool, baby! It's cool!
继续谈  把枪指住我  对了
We still just talking! Come on, point the gun at me! Point the gun at me! There you go
文森特  停手 别做傻事       跟她说没事
Now, Vincent, you just hang back and don't do a goddamn thing  Tell her we're still cool
没事的  小兔兔
We're still cool, Honey Bunny
你还好吧宝贝儿?
How we doing, baby?
我想尿尿  我想回家
L    I gotta go pee  I want to go home
坚持住宝贝儿 你做得很好 我很骄傲
Just hang in there, baby  You're doin' great  I'm proud of you
林戈也为你骄傲  就快没事了
And Ringo's proud of you  It's almost over
跟她说你很骄傲
Tell her you're proud of her
我很骄傲  小兔兔
I'm proud of you, Honey Bunny
我爱你
I love you
我也爱你  小兔兔
I love you, too, Honey Bunny
现在把我的钱包找出来
I want you to go in that bag and find my wallet
哪一个?
Which one is it?
上面写"混帐东西"那个
It's the one that says Bad Motherfucker
那就是我的混帐东西
That's my Bad Motherfucker
打开它  把钱拿出来
Open it up  Take out the money
数一数
Count it
有多少?
How much is there?
一千五
About $1,500
拿去  全都给你
OK, put it in your pocket  It's yours
加上其他人的钱  收获算丰富了
With the rest of those wallets and the register that makes this a pretty successful little score
朱尔斯  你拿一千五给他  按我原则我就毙了他
Jules, you give that fuckin' nimrod $ 1,500 and I'll shoot him on general principle
优兰达  他不会的  文森特 闭上嘴！
No, Yolanda, Yolanda! He ain't gonna do a goddamn motherfuckin' thing  Vince, shut the fuck up!
别激动 尤兰达 继续指着我 宝贝
Come on, Yolanda, stay with me, baby  Now, I ain't givin' it to him, Vincent
我不是给他  我是向他买东西
I'm buyin' somethin' for my money
想知道我买什么吗?
Wanna know what I'm buyin', Ringo?
什么?
What?
你的命 我给你钱 就不用杀你
Your life  I'm givin' you that money so I don't have to kill your ass
你读过圣经吗?
You read the Bible, Ringo?
不常读
Not regularly, no
有段经文  我熟记在心
Well, there's this passage I got memorized
《以西结书》二十五章十七节
Ezekiel 25:17
正直之人的道路
The path of the righteous man
被小人的自私贪婪和恶人的暴虐专政所笼罩
is beset on all sides by the inequities of the selfish and the tyranny of evil men
以仁慈善良之名引领弱小穿越黑暗之谷的“牧羊人”
Blessed is he who in the name of charity and good will
必将得到神的护佑
shepherds the weak through the Valley of Darkness
因为他守护兄弟同胞、拯救迷途羔羊
for he is truly his brother's keeper and the finder of lost children
我将对那些毒害和屠杀我同胞的人
And I will strike down upon thee with great vengeance and furious anger
充满巨大的仇恨和爆裂的怒火
those who attempt to poison and destroy My brothers
当我复仇之焰吞噬你的那刻 你会知道我的名字 叫做上帝
And you will know I am the Lord when I lay My vengeance upon you
这段话我说了很多年 听过的人都会死
Now, I been sayin' that shit for years  And if you heard it, that meant your ass
我从未仔细想过其中的涵意
I never gave much thought to what it meant
只觉得是干掉某个混蛋前冷血的说辞
I just thought it was some cold-blooded shit to say to a motherfucker before I popped a cap in his ass
但今早发生了一件事  让我开始反省
But I saw some shit this mornin' made me think twice
之前我认为你是恶人 我是正直的人
See, now I'm thinkin' maybe it means you're the evil man and I'm the righteous man
我的9毫米口径手枪像牧羊人般保护我穿越黑暗之谷
and Mr  Nine-millimeter here he's the shepherd protecting my righteous ass in the Valley of Darkness
或者你是正直之人 我是“牧羊人”
Or it could mean you're the righteous man and I'm the shepherd
而邪恶自私的是这个世界
and it's the world that's evil and selfish
我很喜欢这个解释 但是也不对
Now, I'd like that  But that shit ain't the truth
事实是你是弱者  而我是那暴虐的恶魔
The truth is you're the weak and I am the tyranny of evil men
但我很努力…林戈
But I'm tryin', Ringo
我真的非常努力想成为慈悲的“牧羊人”
I'm tryin' real hard to be the shepherd
走吧
Go on
我们最好赶快走人
I think we should be leaving now
真是个好主意
Yeah, that's probably a good idea
字幕：发条天天
纯业余制作 语无伦次 漏洞百出 欢迎指教
ljt_chinese@aliyun.com